<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 6/17/2023 1:39:49 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_REBELLION_WEAK_DESC">
			<Text>Jodo Shinshu Rebellion (Weak)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_REBELLION_MODERATE_DESC">
			<Text>Jodo Shinshu Rebellion (Medium)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_REBELLION_STRONG_DESC">
			<Text>Jodo Shinshu Rebellion (Strong)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_REBELLION_WEAK_STRATEGY">
			<Text>At least 33% of this City's citizens follow [ICON_RELIGION_JODO_SHINSHU] Jodo Shinshu Buddhism. Negative penalties will be felt by this City as more Social Policies in the Uprising Social Policy Branch are unlocked by the Ikko-Ikki clan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_REBELLION_MODERATE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>At least 66% of this City's citizens follow [ICON_RELIGION_JODO_SHINSHU] Jodo Shinshu Buddhism. Negative penalties will be felt by this City as more Social Policies in the Uprising Social Policy Branch are unlocked by the Ikko-Ikki clan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_REBELLION_STRONG_STRATEGY">
			<Text>100% of this City's citizens follow [ICON_RELIGION_JODO_SHINSHU] Jodo Shinshu Buddhism. Negative penalties will be felt by this City as more Social Policies in the Uprising Social Policy Branch are unlocked by the Ikko-Ikki clan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_REBELLION_PEDIA">
			<Text>The populist teachings of Jodo Shinshu has taken hold of the population. The peasants seek to overthrow the existing samurai order in favor of peasant rule. As such, chaos has sown amongst the population. You must act quickly to remove the religious pressure from this city!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_MAGISTRATE_OFFICE">
			<Text>Magistrate Office</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_MAGISTRATE_OFFICE_PEDIA">
			<Text>In feudal Japan, a magistrate's office, known as "bugyosho" or "machiya," held a vital role in the governance and administration of local regions. These offices served as centers of authority, where magistrates, or "bugyo," carried out their duties of enforcing the law, resolving disputes, and maintaining order. Situated in prominent locations within towns or cities, magistrate's offices were often imposing structures designed to convey a sense of power and authority. Within their walls, magistrates presided over court hearings, issued judgments, and oversaw the daily affairs of their jurisdiction. These offices also provided a platform for citizens to voice their concerns, seek justice, and present petitions. Magistrate's offices became hubs of social interaction, where community members would gather to witness trials, engage in negotiations, and participate in local governance. Through their administration of justice and the exercise of power, magistrate's offices played a crucial role in maintaining law and order, resolving conflicts, and upholding societal harmony in feudal Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_MAGISTRATE_OFFICE_HELP">
			<Text>-1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] from Distress and Poverty.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When built in an [ICON_OCCUPIED] Occupied City, also eliminates extra [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Unhappiness.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_MAGISTRATE_OFFICE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Magistrate Office reduces the unhappiness in your Cities due to Distress and Poverty, helping you manage the happiness of your clan. It is also vital to establish Magistrate Offices quickly in cities you capture, especially if you're intent upon conquering a bunch of them.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_GRANARY_HELP">
			<Text>40% of [ICON_FOOD] Food is carried over after a new [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizen is born. Each source of [ICON_RES_WHEAT] Wheat, [ICON_RES_BANANA] Bananas, and [ICON_RES_DEER] Deer worked by this City produce +1 [ICON_FOOD] Food.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Allows [ICON_FOOD] Food to be moved from this city along trade routes inside your civilization.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_GRANARY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Granary decreases the amount of [ICON_FOOD] Food a city needs to increase in size by 40%. Build Granaries in cities that you want to grow large over time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_RICE_PADDY">
			<Text>Rice Paddy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_RICE_PADDY_PEDIA">
			<Text>A rice paddy, also known as a rice field or rice terrace, is an agricultural landscape specifically cultivated for the purpose of growing rice. It is a fundamental component of rice farming, which is prevalent in many regions across Asia. Rice paddies are typically constructed on flat or gently sloping terrain and are carefully shaped and irrigated to control water levels. They are divided into small, leveled plots, separated by mud or earthen walls, to enable efficient water management. Rice seeds are planted in these flooded plots, allowing the rice plants to grow in submerged conditions. Throughout the growth cycle, the water levels are adjusted to suit different stages of rice cultivation. Rice paddies require diligent maintenance, including periodic weeding, pest control, and soil management. Harvesting of the mature rice grains takes place once the plants have ripened and turned golden. Rice paddies not only serve as the primary source of rice production but also contribute to the ecological balance, acting as habitats for various species of plants and animals. They also have cultural significance, often being associated with traditional farming practices and rural landscapes in many parts of the world.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_RICE_PADDY_HELP">
			<Text>+10% [ICON_FOOD] Food. Each source of [ICON_RES_RICE] Rice worked by this City produces +1 [ICON_FOOD] Food.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]City have at least one source of [ICON_RES_RICE] Rice improved nearby.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_RICE_PADDY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Rice Paddy can only be constructed in a city with an improved source of [ICON_RES_RICE] Rice nearby. It increases the city's [ICON_FOOD] Food output, and should be built to allow your cities to grow extremely fast.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_SAKE_DEN">
			<Text>Sake Den</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_SAKE_DEN_PEDIA">
			<Text>During feudal Japan, sake dens, also known as "Izakaya", played an important role in the social fabric of Japanese society. These establishments originated as humble sake breweries but evolved into gathering places where locals would come to enjoy sake and camaraderie. In a time of strict social hierarchies and rigid class divisions, sakaya provided a space where people from different walks of life could intermingle, share stories, and forge connections. Sake dens often became popular meeting spots for samurai, merchants, artists, and commoners alike, fostering a sense of community and relaxation amidst the demands of feudal life. The sakaya owners, known as "sakanaya," acted as both brewers and hosts, carefully selecting and serving a range of sake to cater to different tastes. These sake dens became cultural hubs, nurturing the arts and serving as venues for poetry recitals, performances, and intellectual discourse. With their warm ambiance, lively atmosphere, and the ever-flowing sake, sake dens in feudal Japan left an indelible mark on the social fabric and drinking culture of the time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_SAKE_DEN_HELP">
			<Text>City must have 5 [ICON_CITIZEN] Population. Maximum 3 Sake Dens may be built in your clan. -1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Unhappiness from Boredom. In addition to the [ICON_GOLD] Gold, the Sake Den provides 1 additional Spy for your clan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_SAKE_DEN_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Sake Den is an incredibly strong building, boosting a City's [ICON_GOLD] Gold generation, [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness, and allowing recruitment of spies for your clan. Build Sake Dens in your strongest cities and combine them with other Gold-generation cities to fund your armies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_SHRINE_HELP">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_PEACE] Faith for every 5 [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizens in this City.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_SHRINE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Shrine increases the [ICON_PEACE] Faith output of the city, speeding up the rate at which you can spread religions.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_NINJUTSU_SCHOOL">
			<Text>Ninjutsu School</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_NINJUTSU_SCHOOL_PEDIA">
			<Text>A ninjutsu school, often referred to as a "ninja dojo," is a training center dedicated to the study and practice of ninjutsu, the traditional martial art and espionage techniques associated with the historical ninja of Japan. These schools provide a structured curriculum for individuals interested in learning the various skills and principles of ninjutsu, which include stealth, unarmed combat, weapons proficiency, disguise, espionage, and survival techniques. In a ninjutsu school, students, known as "shinobi" or "ninja," undergo rigorous training under the guidance of experienced instructors, who impart knowledge on specialized techniques and strategies passed down through generations. The training typically encompasses physical conditioning, weaponry training, agility drills, meditation, and the understanding of the principles of strategy and deception. Students are also encouraged to cultivate a mindset of adaptability, resourcefulness, and discipline. Ninjutsu schools aim to preserve and transmit the ancient art of the ninja while emphasizing its practical applications in self-defense, personal development, and the preservation of historical traditions.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_NINJUTSU_SCHOOL_HELP">
			<Text>Provides two additional spies and levels up all your existing spies. Can only be built in a city with a Sake Den. Must have built at least 3 Sake Dens.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_NINJUTSU_SCHOOL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>An important National Wonder for improving your clan's espionage abilities. The Ninjutsu School provides two additional spies, and levels up all your existing spies. Your clan must have built 3 Sake Dens before constructing the Ninjutsu School.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_CASTLE">
			<Text>Castle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_CASTLE_PEDIA">
			<Text>Castles played a crucial role in the military and political landscape of the time. Built primarily during the late 15th to the 17th century, these castles served as the centers of power for feudal lords, providing defensive capabilities, administrative functions, and symbolizing the lord's authority. Japanese castles often featured multi-tiered structures with walls and moats, designed to withstand sieges and attacks. The main keep, or "tenshu," was the central structure where the lord resided and from which strategic operations were conducted. The castles incorporated elements of traditional Japanese architecture, such as curved roofs, sliding doors, and gardens, while also adopting defensive innovations like stone walls and towers. Some famous examples of Japanese castles include Himeji Castle, Matsumoto Castle, and Osaka Castle, showcasing the architectural and cultural significance of these feudal fortifications.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_CASTLE_HELP">
			<Text>City must have Walls. -1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] from Distress.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_CASTLE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Castle is a Sengoku-era building which increases the city's Defensive Strength by 10 and Hit Points by 25. The city must possess Walls before the Castle can be constructed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_CITADEL">
			<Text>Citadel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_CITADEL_PEDIA">
			<Text>A citadel is a fortified stronghold or a fortified area within a city or town that serves as a defensive structure and a symbol of authority. Citadels have a long history dating back to ancient civilizations, where they were strategically positioned to provide protection against external threats and control over a region. These fortified complexes typically feature high walls, strong gates, and towers for surveillance and defense. Citadels often housed important government or military institutions, such as palaces, barracks, or administrative buildings. Throughout history, citadels played a crucial role in safeguarding territories, providing refuge for inhabitants during times of conflict, and asserting control over a region. They have become iconic landmarks and historical sites, representing the strength and resilience of civilizations from the past. Today, many citadels have been preserved or transformed into museums, offering visitors a glimpse into the military, political, and cultural heritage of the time periods in which they were built.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_CITADEL_HELP">
			<Text>City must have a Castle. -1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] from Distress. Cities gain Indirect Fire, allowing them to fire over obstacles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_CITADEL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Castle is a Late Sengoku-era building which increases the city's Defensive Strength by 10 and Hit Points by 25. The city must possess Walls before the Castle can be constructed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_TEA_HOUSE">
			<Text>Tea House</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_TEA_HOUSE_PEDIA">
			<Text>Tea houses, known as "chashitsu" or "ochaya," have a rich history in feudal Japan as serene retreats dedicated to the art of tea ceremony and the appreciation of matcha, powdered green tea. Originating from Zen Buddhism, tea houses became important spaces for contemplation, tranquility, and social interaction. These elegant establishments were often nestled in carefully manicured gardens or scenic locations, providing a serene environment that reflected the principles of harmony and simplicity. Tea masters, known as "chajin," meticulously crafted the tea house's design, incorporating elements of traditional architecture and aesthetics. The tea ceremony, conducted with grace and precision, became a symbol of hospitality and refined manners. Tea houses became gathering places for intellectuals, samurai, and cultural elites, fostering discussions on philosophy, art, and poetry. With their focus on mindfulness, tea houses in feudal Japan provided an oasis of calm in a bustling world, serving as sanctuaries where the appreciation of tea became a pathway to inner peace and connection with others.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_TEA_HOUSE_HELP">
			<Text>-1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Unhappiness from Boredom. +10% [ICON_CULTURE] Culture in this City.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_TEA_HOUSE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Tea House reduces Boredom in a City and improves the Culture output of the City. Build these when you want to help combat Unhappiness from Boredom and research Social Policies faster.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_NOH_THEATER">
			<Text>Noh Theater</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_NOH_THEATER_PEDIA">
			<Text>Noh theater, a traditional form of Japanese performing arts, holds a rich historical significance in feudal Japan. Developed during the 14th century, Noh theater became an integral part of courtly culture and the entertainment of the aristocracy. The theater itself, known as a "Noh stage" or "Nohgakudo," embodied a unique blend of simplicity and elegance. Constructed with natural materials, the stage featured a distinctive structure adorned with intricate woodwork and painted backdrops. Noh theaters were often found within the premises of shrines, temples, or feudal lord residences. These venues served as hallowed spaces for performances that combined music, dance, and poetic dialogue to convey stories rooted in mythology, folklore, and historical events. Noh theater also provided a platform for skilled actors, musicians, and chorus members to showcase their talents and artistic prowess. With its deep symbolism and spiritual undertones, Noh theater offered audiences a profound and contemplative experience, exploring themes of beauty, impermanence, and the human condition. In feudal Japan, Noh theaters stood as cultural sanctuaries, preserving and propagating the captivating artistry and poetic depth of this timeless theatrical tradition.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_NOH_THEATER_HELP">
			<Text>-1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Unhappiness from Boredom.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_NOH_THEATER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Noh Theater reduces Boredom in a City and improves its Culture output. Build these when you want to help combat Unhappiness from Boredom and research Social Policies faster.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_SUMO_TOURNEY">
			<Text>Sumo Wrestling Tourney</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_SUMO_TOURNEY_PEDIA">
			<Text>A sumo wrestling tournament, known as a "basho," is a highly anticipated and traditional event in Japan, showcasing the ancient sport of sumo wrestling. These tournaments take place several times throughout the year in major cities such as Tokyo, Osaka, and Nagoya. The basho lasts for 15 days, with wrestlers, or "rikishi," from various sumo stables competing against each other in a round-robin format. Each day of the tournament features exciting matches between the rikishi, who strive to push, throw, or force their opponents out of the circular ring, called a "dohyo." The top-ranked wrestlers, known as "yokozuna," attract particular attention and have a special status in the sport. Sumo tournaments are steeped in tradition, with rituals, ceremonies, and distinctive customs that accompany the matches. The atmosphere in the venue is electrifying, with spectators cheering for their favorite rikishi and immersing themselves in the unique cultural experience of sumo. Attending a sumo wrestling tournament offers a captivating glimpse into the ancient Japanese sport, its rituals, and the incredible strength and technique displayed by the sumo wrestlers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_SUMO_TOURNEY_HELP">
			<Text>-1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Unhappiness from Boredom. When completed in a City, it automatically begins a "We Love the King Day!" for 10 turns.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_SUMO_TOURNEY_STRATEGY">
			<Text></Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_GOLDEN_PAVILION">
			<Text>Golden Pavilion</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_GOLDEN_PAVILION_PEDIA">
			<Text>The Golden Pavilion, also known as Kinkaku-ji, is a stunning Zen Buddhist temple located in Kyoto, Japan. Renowned for its exquisite beauty and tranquil surroundings, the pavilion stands as a testament to the rich cultural heritage of Japan. Its upper two floors are covered in shimmering gold leaf, creating a breathtaking sight that reflects on the surrounding pond. Originally built as a retirement villa for a shogun in the 14th century, the Golden Pavilion has withstood the test of time, surviving fires and war to become a UNESCO World Heritage site and a beloved symbol of Japanese architecture and spirituality. Visitors from around the world come to admire its harmonious blend of natural and man-made beauty, making it a must-see destination for those seeking serenity and cultural immersion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_GOLDEN_PAVILION_HELP">
			<Text></Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_GOLDEN_PAVILION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"What transforms this world is knowledge. Do you see what I mean? Nothing else can change anything in this world. Knowledge alone is capable of transforming the world, while at the same time leaving it exactly as it is. When you look at the world with knowledge, you realize that things are unchangeable and at the same time are constantly being transformed."[NEWLINE][TAB]- Yukio Mishima[NEWLINE]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_HORYUJI">
			<Text>Horyu-ji</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_HORYUJI_PEDIA">
			<Text>Horyu-ji, located in Nara, Japan, is a Buddhist temple complex that holds immense historical and cultural significance. Founded in the early 7th century, Horyu-ji is one of the oldest wooden structures in the world and stands as a testament to the architectural and artistic achievements of ancient Japan. The temple complex consists of several buildings, including the iconic five-story pagoda and the main hall, known as the Golden Hall or Kondo. These structures showcase the distinct architectural style of the Asuka period, characterized by intricate wood carvings, ornate roof tiles, and the use of traditional building techniques. Horyu-ji also houses a vast collection of Buddhist artifacts, including statues, scriptures, and relics, many of which are considered national treasures or important cultural properties.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_HORYUJI_HELP">
			<Text>Provides a free Shrine in all Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_HORYUJI_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Purification in Shinto lifts the burden from the shoulders of the individual and washes it away."[NEWLINE][TAB]- Stuart D. B. Picken[NEWLINE]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_HONGANJI">
			<Text>Hongan-ji</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_HONGANJI_PEDIA">
			<Text>Hongan-ji, also known as Nishi Hongan-ji, is a prominent Buddhist temple located in Kyoto, Japan. Founded in the 16th century, it belongs to the Jodo Shinshu school of Buddhism and is considered one of the largest wooden structures in the world. The temple complex encompasses multiple buildings, including the Goei-do (Founder's Hall) and Amidado (Hall of Amida Buddha). Hongan-ji has a rich historical significance, as it played a pivotal role in the development and propagation of Jodo Shinshu Buddhism during a time of social and political upheaval in Japan. The temple has endured numerous reconstructions and fires throughout its history, showcasing the resilience and dedication of its followers. Today, Hongan-ji serves as a spiritual center and a place for Buddhist ceremonies, study, and worship. It also houses important cultural artifacts, such as ancient Buddhist scriptures and works of art. As an architectural marvel and a symbol of religious devotion, Hongan-ji continues to attract visitors from around the world, offering a glimpse into the profound teachings and cultural heritage of Jodo Shinshu Buddhism.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_HONGANJI_HELP">
			<Text></Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_HONGANJI_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"May the wisdom of the All-Compassionate One so shine within our hearts and minds, that the mists of error and the foolish vanity of self be dispelled. So shall we understand the changing nature of existence and reach spiritual peace."[NEWLINE][TAB]- Shinran[NEWLINE]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_KIYOMIZU_TEMPLE">
			<Text>Kiyomizu Temple</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_KIYOMIZU_TEMPLE_PEDIA">
			<Text>Kiyomizu-dera Temple, located in Kyoto, Japan, is an iconic and historic Buddhist temple that holds great cultural and religious significance. Founded in the 8th century, the temple is known for its impressive wooden structure, which was constructed without the use of any nails. The main hall of Kiyomizu-dera, known as the Hondo, stands on a steep hillside, offering visitors panoramic views of the surrounding city and the beautiful Otawa Waterfall below.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Kiyomizu-dera is a popular destination for tourists and locals alike, especially during the spring cherry blossom season and the autumn foliage season when the temple and its surrounding maple trees create a stunning display of colors. The temple complex also features various other structures and shrines, including the Jishu Shrine dedicated to love and matchmaking.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The temple holds deep spiritual significance for worshippers, who visit to pray for good fortune, success in their endeavors, and general well-being. Visitors can also participate in traditional rituals, such as drinking from the Otawa Waterfall, believed to have healing properties, and receiving blessings from the temple's resident priests.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_KIYOMIZU_TEMPLE_HELP">
			<Text></Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_KIYOMIZU_TEMPLE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"In Kyoto,[NEWLINE]hearing the cuckoo,[NEWLINE]I long for Kyoto."[NEWLINE][TAB]- Basho[NEWLINE]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_KASUGA_TAISHA">
			<Text>Kasuga Taisha</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_KASUGA_TAISHA_PEDIA">
			<Text>Kasuga Taisha, located in Nara, Japan, is a renowned Shinto shrine that holds deep historical and cultural significance. Established in the 8th century, it is dedicated to the deities of Kasuga Shrine, known as the guardian gods of the Fujiwara clan, a powerful family during the Heian period. Kasuga Taisha is known for its striking vermilion-colored buildings and numerous stone lanterns that line the paths leading to the shrine. The shrine's architectural style, called Kasuga-zukuri, is characterized by its intricate wooden structures and the use of cypress bark on the roofs. Kasuga Taisha is also surrounded by a picturesque forest, known as Kasugayama Primeval Forest, which is considered sacred and has been designated as a UNESCO World Heritage site. The shrine plays a significant role in the local community and hosts several festivals throughout the year, including the Setsubun Mantoro festival where lanterns are illuminated, creating a magical atmosphere. Kasuga Taisha stands as a testament to the enduring traditions and spiritual reverence of Shintoism in Japan, attracting visitors from around the world who come to appreciate its architectural beauty, serene ambiance, and rich cultural heritage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_KASUGA_TAISHA_HELP">
			<Text>Receive +25 [ICON_GOLD] Gold when purchasing units and buildings with [ICON_PEACE] Faith. -1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Unrest from Religious Unrest in all Cities. Provides a free Shrine in the city in which it was built.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_KASUGA_TAISHA_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"To be fully alive is to have an aesthetic perception of life because a major part of the world’s goodness lies in its often unspeakable beauty."[NEWLINE][TAB]– Yukitaka Yamamoto[NEWLINE]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_OMOTESENKE">
			<Text>Omotesenke</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_OMOTESENKE_PEDIA">
			<Text>Omotesenke is one of the three main schools or "ryuha" of the Japanese tea ceremony, a centuries-old tradition of preparing and serving matcha, powdered green tea. Established in the 17th century by Sen Sotan, Omotesenke emphasizes the beauty of simplicity and the concept of "wabi-sabi," appreciating the beauty in imperfection and transience. The school focuses on creating a serene and harmonious atmosphere during the tea ceremony, with meticulous attention to details such as tea utensils, tea rooms, and the art of tea preparation itself. Omotesenke's teachings and philosophy have been passed down through generations, shaping the way participants engage in the tea ceremony and fostering an appreciation for the essence of Japanese aesthetics and culture. Today, Omotesenke continues to play a significant role in preserving and promoting the art of the tea ceremony, enriching the lives of those who partake in this ancient and revered tradition.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_OMOTESENKE_HELP">
			<Text>-1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Unhappiness from Boredom in every City. A free Tea House appears in this City. +50 [ICON_PEACE] Faith when a new Citizen is born in this City (scaling with era).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_WONDER_OMOTESENKE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Tea with us became more than an idealization of the form of drinking; it is a religion of the art of life.... Teaism was Taoism in disguise."[NEWLINE][TAB]– Okakura Kakuzo[NEWLINE]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_MONASTERY_DESC">
			<Text>Jodo Shinshu Temple</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_MONASTERY_HELP">
			<Text>+50% religious pressure emanating from this city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BUILDING_MONASTERY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Jodo Shinshu Temples increase a city's [ICON_PEACE] Faith and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture output. It also increases the religious pressure of this city, allowing your religion to spread to other Cities faster.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>