<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 6/24/2023 3:31:44 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITYSTATE_ASHIKAGA">
			<Text>Ashikaga Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITYSTATE_ASHIKAGA_ADJ">
			<Text>Ashikaga</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITYSTATE_HONMA">
			<Text>Honma Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITYSTATE_HONMA_ADJ">
			<Text>Honma</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ASHIKAGA_TEXT">
			<Text>The Ashikaga clan, founded by Ashikaga Takauji in the late 13th century, became one of the most influential samurai clans in Japanese history. Takauji initially supported the Kamakura shogunate but later turned against it, leading to its downfall and the establishment of the Ashikaga shogunate in 1336. The Ashikaga clan ruled over Japan for nearly two and a half centuries, with Kyoto as their capital. The Ashikaga shogunate saw periods of relative stability and prosperity, marked by cultural achievements and the flourishing of Zen Buddhism. However, the clan also faced internal power struggles, which eventually led to its decline. The Ōnin War (1467-1477), a devastating conflict between rival factions within the clan, shattered the shogunate's authority and plunged Japan into a prolonged period of civil unrest known as the Sengoku period. Despite their eventual loss of power, the Ashikaga clan's legacy remains significant, as they profoundly influenced Japanese feudal society, art, and the growth of Zen Buddhism.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_HONMA_TEXT">
			<Text>The Honma clan was a samurai family that emerged in Japan during the Sengoku period. Serving as loyal retainers of the powerful Uesugi clan, the Honma clan gained recognition for their military prowess and unwavering loyalty. Led by skilled leaders such as Honma Yoshitaka and Honma Kazumasu, they actively participated in major battles, including the renowned Battles of Kawanakajima against the Takeda clan. The Honma clan's expertise in archery, spear-fighting, and horseback riding earned them a reputation as formidable warriors. While internal conflicts and the tumultuous Sengoku era posed challenges, the Honma clan's contributions to the Uesugi clan's military campaigns are recognized as part of their legacy in Japanese feudal history.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>