<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 5/30/2023 7:54:20 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_BARBARIAN_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Ronin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SHIMAZU_DESC">
			<Text>Shimazu Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SHIMAZU_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Shimazu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SHIMAZU_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Shimazu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_OTOMO_DESC">
			<Text>Otomo Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_OTOMO_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Otomo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_OTOMO_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Otomo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_MORI_DESC">
			<Text>Mori Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_MORI_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Mori</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_MORI_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Mori</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_CHOSOKABE_DESC">
			<Text>Chosokabe Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_CHOSOKABE_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Chosokabe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_CHOSOKABE_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Chosokabe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_UESUGI_DESC">
			<Text>Uesugi Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_UESUGI_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Uesugi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_UESUGI_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Uesugi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TAKEDA_DESC">
			<Text>Takeda Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TAKEDA_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Takeda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TAKEDA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Takeda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_HOJO_DESC">
			<Text>Hojo Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_HOJO_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Hojo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_HOJO_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Hojo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TOKUGAWA_DESC">
			<Text>Tokugawa Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TOKUGAWA_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Tokugawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TOKUGAWA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Tokugawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_IKKO_IKKI_DESC">
			<Text>Ikko-Ikki</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_IKKO_IKKI_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Ikko-Ikki</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_IKKO_IKKI_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Ikko-Ikki</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_JAPAN_DESC">
			<Text>Oda Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_JAPAN_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Oda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_JAPAN_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Oda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_DATE_DESC">
			<Text>Date Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_DATE_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Date</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_DATE_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Date</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_IMAGAWA_DESC">
			<Text>Imagawa Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_IMAGAWA_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Imagawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_IMAGAWA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Imagawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_ODA_DESC">
			<Text>Oda Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_ODA_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Oda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_ODA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Oda</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_SHIMAZU_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_SHIMAZU_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Shimazu clan of Japan holds a storied history that spans centuries, marked by their influence, military prowess, and strategic alliances. Originating from the Satsuma province in Kyushu, the Shimazu clan emerged as a formidable force during the Sengoku Jidai, the era of warring states.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The clan's early history can be traced back to the 12th century when they rose to power under the leadership of Shimazu Tadahisa. Over time, the Shimazu clan expanded their territories through shrewd diplomacy, strategic marriages, and military conquests. They skillfully navigated the complex political landscape, forming alliances with neighboring clans such as the Otomo and Ryuzoji.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]One of the notable figures in Shimazu clan history is Shimazu Yoshihiro, who played a pivotal role in the Battle of Sekigahara in 1600. Known for his fearless bravery and tactical brilliance, Yoshihiro led his forces against the powerful Tokugawa clan and became renowned for his skillful use of the yari (spear) on the battlefield. Although the Shimazu clan fought valiantly, they ultimately sided with the losing Western army, resulting in the loss of their territories.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Despite their defeat at Sekigahara, the Shimazu clan rebounded and reestablished their power in the Satsuma domain. Under the rule of Shimazu Nariakira in the mid-19th century, the clan embraced Western influences and implemented a range of modernization reforms in their domain. Nariakira's efforts helped Satsuma become a center of Western learning and technology, contributing to the larger movement of Meiji Restoration that led to the downfall of the Tokugawa shogunate.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the Meiji period, the Shimazu clan transitioned from being feudal lords to influential figures in the new government. Shimazu Tadayoshi, a descendant of the clan, served as a prominent statesman and played a role in shaping Japan's early modernization efforts. The Shimazu clan continued to hold political influence and contributed to the nation's development throughout the subsequent eras.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Today, the Shimazu clan's legacy endures, with descendants still recognized as prominent figures in various fields, including politics, academia, and the arts. The clan's rich history and their impact on the region of Satsuma and Japanese society as a whole make them an integral part of Japan's historical tapestry.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_OTOMO_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_OTOMO_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Otomo clan of Japan has a rich and complex history that spans several centuries, leaving an indelible mark on the nation's political and cultural landscape. Originating from the Kyushu region, the Otomo clan rose to prominence during the Sengoku Jidai, the era of warring states.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The clan's earliest known ancestor was Otomo Sorin, who established the foundation of the clan's power in the 16th century. Known for his astute diplomacy, Sorin forged strategic alliances with neighboring clans, including the Shimazu and the Mori, which helped solidify the Otomo clan's position in Kyushu. Through both military conquests and political maneuvering, the Otomo clan expanded their territory and influence across the region.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]One of the defining aspects of the Otomo clan was their early embrace of Christianity. Sorin and subsequent clan leaders, such as Otomo Sorin and Otomo Yoshimune, converted to Christianity and welcomed Jesuit missionaries to their domains. This religious affiliation brought new ideas, technology, and trade networks to the Otomo clan, setting them apart from other daimyo in Japan. However, their conversion also sparked tensions with other clans and the ruling authorities who saw Christianity as a potential threat to traditional Japanese values.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Otomo clan faced significant challenges during the late 16th century when Toyotomi Hideyoshi launched his campaigns to unify Japan. Initially, the Otomo clan resisted Hideyoshi's advances, but they eventually succumbed to overwhelming pressure and allied with him. This alliance allowed the Otomo clan to maintain some autonomy and retain their territories, albeit under the watchful eye of the Toyotomi regime.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Following the fall of the Toyotomi regime, the Otomo clan aligned themselves with Tokugawa Ieyasu, who emerged as the de facto ruler of Japan. Under Tokugawa rule, the Otomo clan continued to exert influence and participate in the political affairs of Kyushu. However, as the Edo period progressed, their power gradually diminished, and they transitioned from being daimyo to local administrators under the Tokugawa shogunate.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Today, the Otomo clan's legacy endures, with descendants who have contributed to various fields, including politics, academia, and the arts. The clan's early adoption of Christianity and their role in regional politics make them a fascinating part of Japan's history. The Otomo clan's story is a testament to the complex interplay between religion, diplomacy, and power during the transformative Sengoku Jidai era.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_MORI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_MORI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Mori clan, with its roots in the Chugoku region of Japan, has a storied history that spans several centuries and played a pivotal role during the Sengoku Jidai period. Known for their military prowess, strategic acumen, and political maneuvering, the Mori clan left an indelible mark on the history of Japan.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The origins of the Mori clan can be traced back to the late 12th century, when the family served as local warriors under the powerful Kikkawa clan. It was during the leadership of Mori Tokichika that the clan began to rise in prominence. Tokichika distinguished himself in battle, displaying remarkable martial skill and strategic thinking.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The turning point for the Mori clan came when Mori Motonari assumed leadership in the late 15th century. Motonari's strategic brilliance and diplomatic finesse propelled the clan to new heights. He skillfully navigated the complex political landscape of the Sengoku Jidai, forging alliances with other powerful clans and expanding the Mori clan's influence.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Motonari's most notable achievement was the implementation of his three-arrow strategy, symbolizing the importance of unity among his three sons: Mori Takamoto, Kikkawa Motoharu, and Kobayakawa Takakage. This strategy enabled the clan to maintain a strong and cohesive front against their enemies, making them a formidable force on the battlefield.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Under Motonari's leadership, the Mori clan achieved several significant victories, including the Battle of Miyajima in 1555 and the Battle of Itsukushima in 1557. These triumphs solidified the clan's control over the Aki and Bingo provinces, establishing a strong base of power in the Chugoku region.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Following Motonari's death, his sons continued to uphold the clan's legacy and expand its influence. Mori Terumoto, the grandson of Motonari, became the most prominent figure of the next generation. Terumoto played a pivotal role in the late Sengoku Jidai, particularly during the events leading up to the Battle of Sekigahara in 1600.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]At the Battle of Sekigahara, the Mori clan initially aligned with the Western Army, opposing the Tokugawa forces. However, they were ultimately defeated, leading to a significant decline in the clan's power. Terumoto managed to retain some of their territories, but the Mori clan's influence was greatly diminished under the Tokugawa shogunate.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Despite their reduced power, the Mori clan continued to play a role in the political landscape of Japan. Some members of the clan served as administrators under the Tokugawa shogunate, maintaining a level of influence within their domains.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Today, the Mori clan's legacy endures, and their contributions to Japanese history are celebrated. Their military prowess, strategic brilliance, and ability to forge alliances set them apart as a formidable clan during the Sengoku Jidai period. The Mori clan's story serves as a testament to the complex dynamics of power, diplomacy, and warfare in feudal Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_CHOSOKABE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_CHOSOKABE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Chosokabe clan, a powerful daimyo family in feudal Japan, emerged from the Tosa Province (present-day Kochi Prefecture) and played a significant role during the Sengoku Jidai period. The clan's history is marked by the rise to power of Chosokabe Motochika and their subsequent expansion in Shikoku.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The origins of the Chosokabe clan can be traced back to the late 14th century when Chosokabe Kunichika established himself as a local warrior in Tosa Province. However, it was under the leadership of Kunichika's son, Motochika, that the clan reached its zenith.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Motochika, born in 1539, assumed control of the Chosokabe clan following his father's assassination. At a young age, he displayed remarkable military talent and ambition, setting his sights on unifying the fragmented Tosa Province.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Motochika embarked on a series of military campaigns, clashing with rival clans in Tosa. Through his strategic brilliance and battlefield prowess, he gradually expanded his influence, securing alliances and defeating his opponents. His campaigns culminated in the unification of Tosa Province under the Chosokabe banner.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Having achieved control over Tosa, Motochika turned his attention to Shikoku, the neighboring island. He sought to extend his dominion and establish the Chosokabe clan as a major power in the region.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Motochika's conquest of Shikoku was a formidable challenge. The island was divided among powerful clans, including the powerful Miyoshi and Ichijo families. Undeterred, Motochika launched a series of military campaigns, gradually bringing the provinces of Awa, Sanuki, and Iyo under his control.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]His most notable victory came in 1585 when he successfully captured the strategically significant fortress of Urado. This achievement solidified Motochika's dominance over Shikoku, and he declared himself the "Lord of Shikoku," firmly establishing the Chosokabe clan as a major force in the region.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Motochika's rule over Shikoku was characterized by effective governance and reforms. He implemented land reforms, improving the lives of farmers and peasants. He encouraged economic development, trade, and cultural exchanges, fostering prosperity within his domain.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]However, the Chosokabe clan's expansion drew the attention of the powerful Toyotomi Hideyoshi, who sought to unify Japan under his rule. In 1587, Hideyoshi launched the Kyushu Campaign, aiming to suppress the power of regional daimyo, including Motochika.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Faced with overwhelming force, Motochika chose to surrender to Hideyoshi, losing his conquests in Shikoku. Nonetheless, he retained his domain in Tosa Province under the Toyotomi shogunate. Motochika remained a respected figure and continued to wield influence within his reduced territories.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Chosokabe clan endured beyond Motochika's era. Some members of the clan served under the Tokugawa shogunate, maintaining a level of prominence within their domain. The clan's rich history and legacy continue to be celebrated in Kochi Prefecture, where their stronghold was located.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Chosokabe clan's rise to power, their conquests in Tosa and Shikoku, and their contributions to regional development make them a significant clan of the Sengoku Jidai period. Motochika's ambition, military achievements, and governance highlight their enduring impact on the history of Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_UESUGI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_UESUGI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Uesugi clan, a prominent lineage in Japanese history, traces its origins back to the 12th century. Initially based in the Echigo province, the clan rose to prominence under the leadership of Uesugi Norimasa. However, it was Uesugi Kenshin, the fourth head of the clan, who became the most renowned figure in Uesugi history. Kenshin, known as the "Dragon of Echigo," was a fearsome warrior and a master tactician. He engaged in numerous battles, most notably against his rival, Takeda Shingen, in what became one of the most legendary feuds of the Sengoku Jidai period. Kenshin's military genius, unwavering honor, and adherence to the principles of bushido earned him a place among Japan's greatest samurai.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Following Kenshin's death, the Uesugi clan experienced a decline in power and influence. Internal conflicts and external pressures weakened their position, and they eventually lost control of the Echigo province. Despite their diminished status, the Uesugi clan continued to hold a place of respect and admiration in Japanese history. Their legacy of martial prowess, loyalty, and adherence to the samurai code left an indelible mark on Japanese culture. The Uesugi clan's tale is one of valor, rivalry, and the pursuit of excellence, solidifying their status as an enduring symbol of the samurai spirit in feudal Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_TAKEDA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_TAKEDA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Originating from the Kai Province, the Takeda clan, led by influential leaders such as Takeda Shingen, carved a legacy as fierce warriors and skilled tacticians. Their expertise in cavalry warfare, symbolized by their swift and devastating mounted attacks, left an indelible mark on the battlefield. Despite their ultimate defeat and the decline of their power, the Takeda clan's legacy endures as a testament to their unwavering spirit, unwavering ambition, and significant contributions to the complex tapestry of Japan's feudal history.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_HOJO_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_HOJO_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Hojo clan, a powerful lineage during the Sengoku Jidai period in Japan, established themselves as influential rulers in the Kanto region. Renowned for their military prowess, administrative skills, and expertise in fortress building, the Hojo clan commanded respect and held significant sway over the political landscape. Led by notable figures such as Hojo Ujiyasu, they successfully defended their main stronghold, Odawara Castle, against numerous attacks, solidifying their reputation as formidable defenders. While their ultimate defeat marked the end of their rule, the Hojo clan's legacy endures as a testament to their strategic acumen, cultural patronage, and their lasting impact on the history of feudal Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_TOKUGAWA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_TOKUGAWA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Tokugawa clan, also known as the Tokugawa family, was a powerful and influential lineage that rose to prominence during the Sengoku Jidai period in Japan. The clan's most prominent figure, Tokugawa Ieyasu, played a pivotal role in the unification of Japan and the establishment of the Tokugawa Shogunate, which would rule the country for over 250 years.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Originally a vassal of the powerful Oda and later the Toyotomi clans, Ieyasu skillfully navigated the complex political landscape of the era, forging alliances and expanding his power base. Following the decisive Battle of Sekigahara in 1600, Ieyasu emerged victorious, solidifying his position as a dominant force in Japan.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Under the Tokugawa Shogunate, the clan enacted a strict and centralized governance system known as the Tokugawa bakufu. This system brought stability and peace to the country, fostering economic growth, cultural development, and social order. The Tokugawa clan's rule marked the beginning of the Edo period, characterized by its isolationist policies and the flourishing of arts, literature, and traditional Japanese culture.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Tokugawa clan's influence extended beyond political and military realms. They were patrons of the arts, promoting the growth of various art forms such as kabuki theater and ukiyo-e woodblock prints. They also implemented strict social hierarchies and codes of conduct, emphasizing loyalty and obedience to maintain order within their domains.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]While the Tokugawa Shogunate brought relative stability, it eventually faced challenges from external pressures and internal dissent. The arrival of Western powers in the mid-19th century and growing discontent among certain segments of society eventually led to the downfall of the shogunate in the Meiji Restoration of 1868.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Nevertheless, the legacy of the Tokugawa clan endures as a defining era in Japanese history. Their political astuteness, cultural contributions, and lasting impact on Japan's governance systems have left an indelible mark on the nation's identity.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_IKKO_IKKI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_IKKO_IKKI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Ikko Ikki, also known as the Ikko sect or the Ikkoshu, were a religious and social movement that emerged during the Sengoku Jidai period in Japan. Rooted in Pure Land Buddhism, the Ikko Ikki sought to challenge the authority of the samurai class and promote social equality among the common people.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The movement gained momentum in the Kaga and Echizen provinces, where peasant uprisings and discontent with the ruling class were prevalent. The Ikko Ikki drew support from various social classes, including farmers, artisans, and even some lower-ranking samurai who sympathized with their cause.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Under the leadership of influential figures like Rennyo Shonin, the Ikko Ikki established fortified religious communities called ikkizamurai, which served as both religious centers and defensive strongholds. These communities provided protection to their members and promoted a sense of unity and collective resistance against oppressive feudal lords.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Ikko Ikki's influence extended beyond religious matters. They actively engaged in military conflicts and were known for their fierce resistance against powerful warlords. Their armed forces, composed of both armed peasants and warrior monks, posed a significant challenge to the established samurai order.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Despite their military and social upheaval, the Ikko Ikki ultimately faced defeat as the central authority sought to suppress their movement. However, their resistance and the ideals they espoused left a lasting impact on Japanese society. The Ikko Ikki played a significant role in challenging the rigid social hierarchy of the time, and their struggles paved the way for future movements advocating for greater social equality and justice. Today, their legacy is remembered as a symbol of popular revolt and the pursuit of social change in feudal Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_DATE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_DATE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Date Clan was a powerful and influential samurai clan that emerged during the Sengoku Jidai period in Japan. Originating from the region of Mutsu, in present-day Fukushima Prefecture, the Date clan rose to prominence under the leadership of notable figures such as Date Masamune. Known for their military prowess and strategic acumen, the Date clan played a significant role in the politics and warfare of the time. They controlled a vast domain and were respected for their disciplined armies, skilled warriors, and shrewd diplomacy. The Date clan's legacy extends beyond their military exploits, as they also cultivated a rich cultural tradition, supporting the arts and encouraging the development of the region. Today, the Date clan remains renowned for their contributions to Japanese history and their enduring impact on the cultural heritage of the Tohoku region.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_IMAGAWA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_IMAGAWA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Imagawa clan was a prominent samurai family that held significant influence in the region of Suruga during the Sengoku period in Japan. The clan's origins can be traced back to the 12th century, but it was under the leadership of Imagawa Yoshimoto that their power reached its peak. Yoshimoto expanded the clan's territories through strategic alliances and military campaigns, establishing control over parts of the Tokaido region. However, their rise to prominence was abruptly halted when they clashed with the powerful Oda clan. In the Battle of Okehazama in 1560, Imagawa Yoshimoto was unexpectedly killed by Oda Nobunaga's forces, marking a turning point in the clan's fortunes. Subsequent internal conflicts and the loss of their charismatic leader weakened the Imagawa clan's position, leading to their decline and eventual dissolution. Despite their ultimate defeat, the Imagawa clan's legacy remains significant, particularly in the realm of cultural patronage and diplomacy, as they were known for fostering alliances and supporting the arts during their heyday.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_ODA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_CIV_ODA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Oda clan, led by the renowned warlord Oda Nobunaga, rose to prominence during the Sengoku period in Japan. Nobunaga, known for his ambition and strategic brilliance, aimed to unify the fractured nation under his rule. With the Owari province as their base, the Oda clan embarked on a series of military campaigns, employing innovative tactics and forming strategic alliances. Nobunaga's military prowess, combined with his progressive policies, transformed the clan into a formidable force. However, their journey to dominance was abruptly halted when Nobunaga was betrayed and killed in 1582. Despite his untimely demise, the Oda clan's legacy endured through his loyal retainers, most notably Toyotomi Hideyoshi, who successfully completed Nobunaga's vision and unified Japan. The Oda clan's rise and fall exemplify the volatile nature of the Sengoku period and their significant contributions to shaping Japan's history.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>