<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 5/30/2023 8:17:27 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!-- Entry UI-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO">
			<Text>Shimazu Yoshihiro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_OTOMO_SORIN">
			<Text>Otomo Sorin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_MORI_MOTONARI">
			<Text>Mori Motonari</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA">
			<Text>Chosokabe Motochika</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_UESUGI_KENSHIN">
			<Text>Uesugi Kenshin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TAKEDA_SHINGEN">
			<Text>Takeda Shingen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_HOJO_UJIYASU">
			<Text>Hojo Ujiyasu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU">
			<Text>Tokugawa Ieyasu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_RENNYO">
			<Text>Rennyo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_DATE_MASAMUNE">
			<Text>Date Masamune</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_IMAGAWA_YOSHIMOTO">
			<Text>Imagawa Yoshimoto</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Civilopedia -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_NAME">
			<Text>Shimazu Yoshihiro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Daimyo of the Shimazu Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_LIVED">
			<Text>1535 - 1619 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Shimazu Yoshihiro, a prominent figure in Japanese history, was born in 1535 as the eldest son of Shimazu Takahisa, the daimyo (feudal lord) of the Shimazu clan. Yoshihiro played a significant role in shaping the clan's legacy during the tumultuous Sengoku Jidai period.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Yoshihiro's military career began at a young age, receiving a strict upbringing that instilled discipline and martial prowess. He demonstrated exceptional skill and courage on the battlefield, quickly establishing himself as a formidable warrior. Yoshihiro's combat expertise centered around his mastery of the yari (spear), which became his signature weapon.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Military Dominance</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_TEXT_2">
			<Text>In 1565, at the age of 30, Yoshihiro led his forces in a decisive victory against the Ito clan at the Battle of Okitanawate. This triumph solidified his reputation as a fearsome general and contributed to the expansion of the Shimazu clan's influence in Kyushu. He went on to participate in numerous campaigns, leading his troops with unmatched bravery and tactical brilliance.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]One of Yoshihiro's most iconic moments came during the Battle of Sekigahara in 1600. During this pivotal conflict, he aligned himself with the Western Army, opposing the powerful Tokugawa forces. Known for his unwavering loyalty, Yoshihiro fought valiantly despite being outnumbered and managed to rout a portion of the Tokugawa army. However, the overall outcome favored the Tokugawa forces, leading to their ultimate victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Under Tokugawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Following the defeat at Sekigahara, Yoshihiro's domain was reduced, and he was forced to submit to the Tokugawa shogunate. Despite this setback, he was allowed to retain his lands and maintain the Shimazu clan's presence in Satsuma province. Yoshihiro's diplomatic skills became evident during this period as he skillfully managed his clan's relations with the central government, preserving their autonomy and safeguarding their interests.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Yoshihiro's influence extended beyond the battlefield. He supported cultural and intellectual endeavors, fostering the arts, tea ceremony, and the study of classical literature. Under his patronage, Satsuma became a center of learning and cultural exchange.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Legacy and Death</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Yoshihiro's influence extended beyond the battlefield. He supported cultural and intellectual endeavors, fostering the arts, tea ceremony, and the study of classical literature. Under his patronage, Satsuma became a center of learning and cultural exchange.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Shimazu Yoshihiro passed away in 1619, leaving behind a legacy of military prowess and unwavering loyalty. His contributions to the Shimazu clan's military expansion, his pivotal role in the Battle of Sekigahara, and his efforts in maintaining the clan's autonomy are testament to his significance in Japanese history. Yoshihiro's name continues to evoke admiration and respect, as he remains one of the most celebrated and revered figures of the Sengoku Jidai era.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_OTOMO_SORIN_NAME">
			<Text>Otomo Sorin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_OTOMO_SORIN_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Daimyo of the Otomo Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_OTOMO_SORIN_LIVED">
			<Text>1530 - 1587 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_OTOMO_SORIN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_OTOMO_SORIN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Otomo Sorin, also known as Otomo Yoshishige, was a prominent daimyo and influential figure in the history of Japan. Born in 1530 in Bungo province (present-day Oita Prefecture), Sorin rose to power during the Sengoku Jidai period and became the founder of the Otomo clan's political and military dominance in Kyushu.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sorin began his military career under the service of the Ōtomo clan, initially serving as a retainer to his uncle, Ōtomo Sorinaga. Following his uncle's death, Sorin assumed leadership of the clan and embarked on a series of military campaigns and strategic alliances to expand their influence. He sought to unify the disparate factions within Bungo province and establish stable governance.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_OTOMO_SORIN_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Conversion to Christianity</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_OTOMO_SORIN_TEXT_2">
			<Text>One of Sorin's notable achievements was his conversion to Christianity, which occurred in 1562. Influenced by the arrival of Jesuit missionaries, Sorin embraced Christianity and became one of the earliest daimyo to adopt the faith. This decision had significant consequences for the Otomo clan and their relations with other daimyo and European powers.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Under Sorin's leadership, the Otomo clan actively engaged in diplomacy, forging alliances with neighboring daimyo and European traders. This allowed the clan to acquire Western firearms, knowledge, and technology, bolstering their military strength and giving them a strategic advantage over their rivals. The Otomo clan became a powerful force in Kyushu and played a key role in the political landscape of Japan.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]However, the Otomo clan's adoption of Christianity became a source of conflict with other daimyo and the ruling authorities, who saw it as a potential threat to traditional Japanese culture and values. Sorin faced opposition and hostility from various factions, leading to intermittent conflicts and challenges to his authority.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_OTOMO_SORIN_HEADING_3">
			<Text>War against Toyotomi Hideyoshi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_OTOMO_SORIN_TEXT_3">
			<Text>In 1587, Toyotomi Hideyoshi, a powerful warlord aiming to unify Japan, launched the Kyushu Campaign with the intent to subjugate the Christian daimyo, including Sorin. The Otomo clan initially resisted, but after facing significant military pressure, Sorin eventually surrendered to Hideyoshi in 1589. Despite the defeat, Sorin managed to retain some autonomy and land holdings, continuing to exert influence within Kyushu.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Following his surrender, Sorin focused on rebuilding his domain and cultivating diplomatic relations. He actively engaged in negotiations with Hideyoshi and later with Tokugawa Ieyasu, ultimately aligning with the Tokugawa forces in the Battle of Sekigahara in 1600.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_OTOMO_SORIN_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Legacy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_OTOMO_SORIN_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Otomo Sorin passed away in 1587, leaving a legacy of diplomatic skill, military prowess, and religious tolerance. His conversion to Christianity, strategic alliances, and ability to navigate the complex political landscape of the Sengoku Jidai era made him a significant figure in Japanese history. Sorin's contributions laid the foundation for the Otomo clan's enduring influence in Kyushu and their role in shaping the future of Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_MORI_MOTONARI_NAME">
			<Text>Mori Motonari</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_MORI_MOTONARI_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Daimyo of the Motonari Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_MORI_MOTONARI_LIVED">
			<Text>1497 - 1571 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_MORI_MOTONARI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_MORI_MOTONARI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Mori Motonari, born in 1497 in Aki Province (present-day Hiroshima Prefecture), was a highly esteemed daimyo and military strategist during the Sengoku Jidai period in Japan. He became the patriarch of the Mori clan, a powerful and influential family in the Chugoku region.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_MORI_MOTONARI_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Rise to Power</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_MORI_MOTONARI_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Motonari's rise to power began when he succeeded his father, Mori Hiromoto, as the head of the clan in 1506. In his early years, he faced numerous challenges, including internal strife and external conflicts with neighboring clans. However, Motonari displayed remarkable leadership abilities and a keen strategic mind that enabled him to overcome these obstacles and solidify his position as a formidable daimyo.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]One of Motonari's notable achievements was his ability to forge alliances with other clans, especially the powerful Ouchi clan. Through strategic marriages, political maneuvering, and military cooperation, he formed a robust network of allies that bolstered the Mori clan's strength and territorial expansion. This alliance allowed Motonari to withstand external pressures from rival daimyo and secure a dominant position in the Chugoku region.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_MORI_MOTONARI_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Military Prowess</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_MORI_MOTONARI_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Motonari's military campaigns and tactical brilliance are considered legendary. He adopted a three-arrow strategy, symbolizing his philosophy of unity and balance. The three arrows represented the principle of "One is weak, three are strong," emphasizing the importance of collaboration and cooperation among his three sons: Mori Takamoto, Kikkawa Motoharu, and Kobayakawa Takakage. This strategy proved highly effective, allowing the Mori clan to maintain a cohesive front against their enemies.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]One of Motonari's most significant victories came in the Battle of Miyajima in 1555, where he decisively defeated the Sue clan and solidified his control over Aki Province. Motonari demonstrated his military acumen by utilizing strategic terrain and effectively coordinating his forces to overcome the enemy. This triumph further enhanced his reputation as a master tactician.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Beyond his military prowess, Motonari was known for his astute governance and promotion of cultural and economic development within his domains. He encouraged commerce, supported the arts, and fostered a climate of stability and prosperity. Motonari's rule contributed to the growth of cities like Hiroshima, which flourished under his patronage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_MORI_MOTONARI_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Legacy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_MORI_MOTONARI_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Mori Motonari's legacy extended beyond his lifetime. His three-arrow strategy, military achievements, and diplomatic finesse influenced subsequent generations of leaders in Japan. The Mori clan continued to thrive and play a significant role in Japanese history, with many of his descendants becoming influential figures in the Tokugawa shogunate and the Meiji Restoration.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Motonari's legacy as a wise and visionary daimyo, a skilled military strategist, and a patron of culture solidify his status as one of the most revered figures of the Sengoku Jidai period. His impact on the Chugoku region and his contributions to the history of Japan make him a true icon of the era.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_NAME">
			<Text>Chosokabe Motochika</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Daimyo of the Chosokabe Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_LIVED">
			<Text>1539 - 1599 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Chosokabe Motochika, a prominent daimyo of the Sengoku Jidai period, played a significant role in the history of Japan. Born in 1539 in Tosa Province (present-day Kochi Prefecture), Motochika became the founder and leader of the Chosokabe clan, which would later become a powerful force in Shikoku.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Motochika's early life was marked by political turmoil and conflict within Tosa Province. His father, Chosokabe Kunichika, was assassinated, and Motochika assumed control of the clan at a young age. Faced with adversity, he swiftly consolidated his power and expanded his influence within the region.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Rise to Power</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Motochika's rise to prominence began with his successful campaigns to unify Tosa Province. Through a combination of military prowess, strategic alliances, and skilled diplomacy, he managed to subdue rival clans and bring the entire province under his control. This achievement established the foundation of the Chosokabe clan's power.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]One of Motochika's defining characteristics was his ambition to expand beyond Tosa Province. In pursuit of this goal, he set his sights on conquering neighboring provinces in Shikoku. His military campaigns in Awa, Sanuki, and Iyo brought him into conflict with the powerful clans of Shikoku, including the powerful Miyoshi and Ichijo clans.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Military Success</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Motochika's most renowned victory came in 1585 when he successfully captured the fortress of Urado, effectively establishing his dominance over Shikoku. This triumph solidified his position as a major player in the region and enhanced the prestige of the Chosokabe clan. Motochika adopted the title of "Lord of Shikoku" and ruled over the island with authority.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Beyond his military successes, Motochika is also remembered for his innovative reforms and governance. He implemented land reforms, improving the lives of farmers and peasants under his rule. Motochika's administration fostered economic development, trade, and cultural exchanges, contributing to the prosperity of his domain.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Surrender to Toyotomi Hideyoshi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_TEXT_4">
			<Text>However, Motochika's ambitions eventually led him into conflict with the powerful Toyotomi Hideyoshi, who sought to unify Japan under his rule. In 1587, Hideyoshi launched the Kyushu Campaign, which aimed to suppress the power of regional daimyo, including Motochika. Faced with overwhelming force, Motochika surrendered to Hideyoshi, resulting in the loss of his conquests in Shikoku.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Following his surrender, Motochika retained his domain in Tosa Province under the Toyotomi shogunate. Despite the setback, he remained a respected figure and enjoyed relative autonomy. Motochika passed away in 1599, leaving behind a legacy of ambition, military prowess, and administrative reforms.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Legacy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Chosokabe Motochika's impact on the history of Japan is significant. His successful unification of Tosa Province, conquest of Shikoku, and innovative governance mark him as an influential daimyo of the Sengoku Jidai period. His determination, strategic thinking, and contributions to regional development make him a notable figure in Japanese history.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_UESUGI_KENSHIN_NAME">
			<Text>Uesugi Kenshin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_UESUGI_KENSHIN_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Daimyo of the Uesugi Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_UESUGI_KENSHIN_LIVED">
			<Text>February 18, 1530 - April 19, 1578 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_UESUGI_KENSHIN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_UESUGI_KENSHIN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Uesugi Kenshin, also known as the "Dragon of Echigo," was one of the most renowned and enigmatic figures of the Sengoku Jidai period in Japan. Born in 1530 as Nagao Kagetora, he would later be adopted into the Uesugi clan, becoming Uesugi Kenshin and assuming the leadership of the clan at the age of 14.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Kenshin quickly demonstrated exceptional military skills and leadership qualities. He was a fierce and fearless warrior, known for his unparalleled prowess on the battlefield. Kenshin's mastery of strategy and tactics allowed him to achieve remarkable victories against formidable opponents, most notably his rival Takeda Shingen. The legendary clashes between Kenshin and Shingen, such as the Battle of Kawanakajima, have become the stuff of legends in Japanese history.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Not only was Kenshin a formidable warrior, but he also embodied the virtues of the samurai code, bushido. He was known for his unwavering honor, strict adherence to ethical principles, and deep spirituality. Kenshin was a devout follower of Zen Buddhism and incorporated its teachings into his daily life and military strategies. He was highly respected not only for his military prowess but also for his just and benevolent rule over the Echigo province.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Despite his military achievements, Kenshin faced numerous challenges, including internal conflicts within his clan and external threats from rival warlords. However, he managed to navigate these turbulent waters with strategic alliances and diplomatic maneuvers. Kenshin's charisma and reputation as a fair and honorable leader attracted many followers, and his domain expanded to become one of the most prosperous and culturally vibrant regions of Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_UESUGI_KENSHIN_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Death</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_UESUGI_KENSHIN_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Tragically, Uesugi Kenshin's life was cut short in 1578 under mysterious circumstances. The exact details surrounding his death remain a subject of speculation and debate. Nevertheless, his legacy as a legendary warrior, a paragon of honor, and a patron of the arts and culture endures. Uesugi Kenshin remains an iconic figure in Japanese history, embodying the ideals of the samurai and leaving an indelible mark on the nation's collective memory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_NAME">
			<Text>Takeda Shingen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Daimyo of the Takeda Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_LIVED">
			<Text>1521 - 1573 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Takeda Shingen, born Takeda Harunobu in 1521, was a legendary daimyo and military strategist during the tumultuous Sengoku Jidai period in Japan. As the head of the powerful Takeda clan, he played a significant role in shaping the political landscape and military conflicts of the time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Military Campaigns</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Shingen inherited leadership of the Takeda clan at the age of 15, following the death of his father. He swiftly consolidated his power and embarked on a path of expansion, seeking to extend his influence across the provinces of Kai, Shinano, and Suruga. Shingen's military campaigns were characterized by his innovative tactics, including the famed "shingenjū no ran" or "Divine Wind" strategy, which involved utilizing mounted troops to create rapid and devastating attacks.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]One of Shingen's most notable achievements was his rivalry with Uesugi Kenshin, the daimyo of the Uesugi clan. The two leaders engaged in a series of intense battles at Kawanakajima, each showcasing their exceptional military skills. Although the outcome of the conflicts was often inconclusive, the rivalry between Shingen and Kenshin became legendary, with both men earning a reputation as formidable adversaries.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Shingen's military success was not limited to his conflicts with Uesugi Kenshin. He also expanded his domain by capturing strategic castles and engaging in alliances and strategic marriages. The Takeda clan grew to become one of the most powerful forces in the region, challenging the authority of other prominent daimyo such as Oda Nobunaga and Tokugawa Ieyasu.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Surrender to Toyotomi Hideyoshi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_TEXT_3">
			<Text>However, Motochika's ambitions eventually led him into conflict with the powerful Toyotomi Hideyoshi, who sought to unify Japan under his rule. In 1587, Hideyoshi launched the Kyushu Campaign, which aimed to suppress the power of regional daimyo, including Motochika. Faced with overwhelming force, Motochika surrendered to Hideyoshi, resulting in the loss of his conquests in Shikoku.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Following his surrender, Motochika retained his domain in Tosa Province under the Toyotomi shogunate. Despite the setback, he remained a respected figure and enjoyed relative autonomy. Motochika passed away in 1599, leaving behind a legacy of ambition, military prowess, and administrative reforms.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Reforms</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Beyond his military exploits, Shingen was known for his administrative reforms and patronage of the arts. He established efficient governing systems, implemented land reforms, and promoted economic development within his territories. Shingen's patronage of tea masters, poets, and scholars contributed to the cultural and intellectual growth of the Takeda domain.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Legacy and Death</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Tragically, Shingen's life was cut short in 1573 due to illness, at the age of 53. His death had a profound impact on the power dynamics of the Sengoku period and marked the beginning of the decline of the Takeda clan. However, his legacy as a brilliant military strategist, charismatic leader, and patron of the arts lives on. Takeda Shingen is remembered as one of Japan's most iconic figures, symbolizing the spirit of the samurai and leaving an enduring impact on Japanese history and culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_HOJO_UJIYASU_NAME">
			<Text>Hojo Ujiyasu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_HOJO_UJIYASU_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Daimyo of the Hojo Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_HOJO_UJIYASU_LIVED">
			<Text>1515 - 1571 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_HOJO_UJIYASU_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_HOJO_UJIYASU_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Born in 1515, Ujiyasu came from a lineage of skilled military strategists and administrators, inheriting the responsibilities of leading the Hojo clan at a young age. Ujiyasu's rule was characterized by his efforts to consolidate and expand the influence of the Hojo clan in the Kanto region. He skillfully maneuvered through the complex political landscape, forming alliances and conducting military campaigns to secure his position and protect the clan's territories. Ujiyasu's strategic foresight and diplomatic acumen allowed the Hojo clan to flourish despite the constant conflicts and power struggles of the era.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_HOJO_UJIYASU_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Military Achievements</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_HOJO_UJIYASU_TEXT_2">
			<Text>One of Ujiyasu's notable achievements was his successful defense of Odawara Castle, the clan's main stronghold. His meticulous fortifications and military preparations turned Odawara Castle into an impregnable fortress, withstanding multiple attacks from rival clans. This reputation for fortress building and defensive strategies solidified the Hojo clan's position as a formidable force in the region.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ujiyasu's military campaigns were not limited to defense alone. He also expanded the Hojo clan's influence through offensive operations, conquering neighboring territories and assimilating them into his domain. Ujiyasu's military successes, combined with his ability to balance diplomacy and governance, allowed the Hojo clan to maintain stability and prosperity throughout his rule.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_HOJO_UJIYASU_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Later Campaigns and Defeat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_HOJO_UJIYASU_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Unfortunately, Ujiyasu's reign was marked by ongoing conflicts with the powerful warlord, Takeda Shingen. The two leaders engaged in several battles, often resulting in stalemates or inconclusive outcomes. Despite their rivalry, Ujiyasu and Shingen held a mutual respect for each other's military prowess, which sometimes led to temporary alliances.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ujiyasu's influence began to decline with the rise of Toyotomi Hideyoshi, who sought to unify Japan under his rule. The Hojo clan faced increasing pressure from Hideyoshi's forces, and in 1590, Odawara Castle finally fell after a long siege. Ujiyasu's son, Hojo Ujimasa, surrendered, effectively ending the Hojo clan's rule.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_HOJO_UJIYASU_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Legacy and Defeat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_HOJO_UJIYASU_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Despite their eventual defeat, Ujiyasu's legacy as a skilled military strategist and astute leader endures. The Hojo clan's defensive strategies, political maneuverings, and contributions to the cultural landscape of the Kanto region left an indelible mark on Japanese history. Ujiyasu's reign exemplified the complex dynamics of the Sengoku Jidai period and the resilience of the Hojo clan in the face of relentless challenges.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_NAME">
			<Text>Tokugawa Ieyasu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Daimyo of the Tokugawa Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_LIVED">
			<Text>1543 - 1616 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Tokugawa (last name, first name Ieyasu) is a brilliant military and peacetime strategist. He is the decisive winner of Japan’s chaotic Sengoku period and the architect of the subsequent Edo period.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The chaos of the Sengoku Jidai (period) in Japanese history has become iconic. In the subsequent prosperity and peace of the Edo period, samurai had little to do but entertain each other with stories about the great battles, leaders, and goings-on of that time – ninjas, generals, armies, sieges, and the like. Much of what we imagine about feudal Japan is itself a product of these stories, embellished and romanticized.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Sengoku period was a massive war between rival clans to seek power. The weak Ashikaga shogunate collapsed, leaving the emperor a mere figurehead and the more powerful position of shogun (military guardian of the Emperor) open. For over a century, rival daimyo (regional lords) and samurai (knights) fought for this title. Into the fray, too, came other elements: Christians, armed by Europeans with muskets, the anti-monarchical ikko-ikki, and the ninja – these last being military strategists without a concept of honor who could commit scandalous acts to benefit their lord. Three samurai emerge into the spotlight: Oda Nobunaga, Toyotomi Hideyoshi, and Tokugawa Ieyasu.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]There is a story that reflects an aspect of the personalities and motivations of these leaders. Imagine the three of them sitting together looking at a little bird that refuses to sing. Oda opens with a threat: “bird, if you do not sing, I will kill you.” Hideyoshi tries manipulation, “bird, if you do not sing, I will convince you.” But Tokugawa, the canniest of the three, simply says, “bird, I can wait.” Here, patience and a cool head win the day – and so it was with Japan.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oda, the “demon king,” lived up to his name. As the head of the Oda clan, Nobunaga rallied his troops to sweep across the main island of Japan, defeating the ikko-ikki and removing the Ashikaga shogunate entirely. The last remaining obstacle was the powerful western clan Mori, who may well have been defeated, too, were it not for a betrayal from within Oda’s own ranks. Seeing Akechi, the traitorous general, coming towards him as he sat relatively unguarded having tea in a temple in Kyoto, Oda committed suicide. The to-be shogun Tokugawa, too, fled in the company of the ninja (well, samurai at that time) Hattori Hanzo.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Toyotomi clan was the next to take up Oda’s banner. Former retainer, Toyotomi Hideyoshi, took up the banner and, too, seized temporary control. Indeed, it was under Hideyoshi that Japanese forces sought to take Korea, and not for the last time. But even the greatest of kings dies, and Hideyoshi, with his focus on overseas expansion, had drained the coffers. A succession crisis ensued between clan loyalists and the new Tokugawa clan, itself formed from a regional vassal clan of Oda’s, under Tokugawa Ieyasu. In the climactic Battle of Sekigahara, Tokugawa achieved dominance and set about picking up the pieces.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Japan was a mess. New ideas were flooding in – republicanism (meaning here rule by the people) and Christianity. Guns and European trade, too, presented an issue. Tokugawa singlehandedly stopped this by implementing sakoku – isolation. Japan’s borders would be closed, except for Nagasaki. This would end both the influx of new and dangerous challenges to the new Tokugawa Shogunate but also an end to the kind of foreign adventures that had led to Hideyoshi’s financial woes. Sakoku was… not disastrous for Japan. Local production flourished, and over what became known as the Edo period (Edo being the home of the shogunate), Japan experienced peace and prosperity… and its neighbors no longer had to worry about samurai showing up on their shores.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The system of control here was brutal. There were still nobles, but Tokugawa had an ingenious strategy for controlling them. While nobles ruled their home provinces, their families remained behind as hostages (of a sort) in Edo. This meant that any rebellion could immediately be squashed via a simple threat to the rebel’s family and also the growth of court life in Edo. Bored but wealthy samurai told stories, and would-be warriors fought duels over honor instead of for land. The famous ukiyo-e, the “floating world” of entertainment, grew, as did artists and writers associated with it.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]This was to crack open in the 1800s, with the arrival (and, significantly, threats to not depart) of American ships demanding trade. Japan realized that the world had developed without them and that things like guns and cannons had gotten quite dangerous. While their opening was traumatic, and the subsequent Meiji period eliminated much of the feudal system of Japan, the infrastructure was already in place to enable Meiji to, within a few decades, take on and defeat some of the most powerful states in the world. But that is a story for another time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_RENNYO_NAME">
			<Text>Rennyo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_RENNYO_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Monshu of the Honga-ji Temple</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_RENNYO_LIVED">
			<Text>1415 - 1499 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_RENNYO_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_RENNYO_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Rennyo, also known as Rennyo Shonin or Rennyo Goso, was a prominent figure in the history of the Ikko Ikki movement during the Muromachi period in Japan. He was the eighth abbot of the Honganji temple, the central institution of the Jodo Shinshu sect of Pure Land Buddhism.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rennyo is widely recognized for his efforts in revitalizing and expanding the influence of the Ikko Ikki movement. He played a crucial role in strengthening the religious and social foundations of the Ikko Ikki, attracting a large following of believers and establishing a network of affiliated temples throughout Japan.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Under Rennyo's leadership, the Honganji temple became a powerful and influential institution, both in terms of religious teachings and political influence. He focused on making the teachings of Jodo Shinshu accessible to the common people, emphasizing the importance of faith and the belief in Amida Buddha's salvation. Rennyo's preaching style, characterized by his heartfelt sermons and use of vernacular language, resonated with the masses and contributed to the widespread popularity of the Ikko Ikki movement.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rennyo's influence extended beyond religious matters. He actively engaged in negotiations with feudal lords, seeking alliances and protection for the Ikko Ikki communities. His diplomatic skills and ability to navigate the complex political landscape of the time were instrumental in ensuring the survival and growth of the movement.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Despite facing numerous challenges and opposition from rival factions, Rennyo's leadership and unwavering dedication to the Ikko Ikki movement left a profound impact. His efforts contributed to the spread of Jodo Shinshu Buddhism and the enduring influence of the Ikko Ikki in Japanese society.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Today, Rennyo is revered as a key figure in the history of Pure Land Buddhism and is considered one of the most influential religious leaders of his time. His teachings and legacy continue to inspire and guide followers of Jodo Shinshu Buddhism to seek spiritual awakening and the path to liberation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_DATE_MASAMUNE_NAME">
			<Text>Date Masamune</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_DATE_MASAMUNE_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Daimyo of the Date Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_DATE_MASAMUNE_LIVED">
			<Text>1567 - 1636 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_DATE_MASAMUNE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_DATE_MASAMUNE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Date Masamune, famously known as the "One-Eyed Dragon," was a prominent daimyo and the most renowned leader of the Date clan during the late 16th and early 17th centuries in Japan. Born in 1567, Masamune inherited leadership of the clan at a young age, facing internal conflicts and rivalries.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A notable characteristic of Masamune was his distinct appearance, with one eye covered by an eyepatch. This feature, believed to be a result of smallpox, further enhanced his reputation as a fearsome and charismatic leader. Masamune became known for his strategic vision, tactical brilliance, and his personal bravery on the battlefield.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_DATE_MASAMUNE_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Military Achievements</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_DATE_MASAMUNE_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Masamune's rise to power began with the defeat of his treacherous relatives, allowing him to solidify his control over the Date clan's territories in the region of Mutsu. With a strong ambition and a vision for expansion, Masamune embarked on a series of successful military campaigns, rapidly expanding his domain and establishing alliances with other powerful clans.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Masamune's military prowess was complemented by his diplomatic skills, as he maintained favorable relations with the central government in Kyoto, securing important positions and recognition. He skillfully navigated the complex political landscape of the time, balancing between loyalty to the Toyotomi and Tokugawa factions.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_DATE_MASAMUNE_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Legacy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_DATE_MASAMUNE_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Beyond his military achievements, Masamune also fostered the cultural and economic development of his territories. He encouraged the growth of commerce and trade, supporting artisans, and promoting the arts. His patronage of cultural activities, including tea ceremonies, Noh theater, and poetry, further elevated his status and the prestige of the Date clan.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Masamune's influence extended beyond his lifetime. His legacy is not only tied to his military achievements but also to his efforts in promoting regional development and cultural exchange. The city of Sendai, which he founded, remains a lasting testament to his vision and leadership.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Today, Masamune is revered as a legendary figure in Japanese history, symbolizing the indomitable spirit of the samurai and the resilience of the Date clan. His legacy continues to inspire admiration and fascination, and his contributions to the history and culture of Japan remain widely celebrated.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_IMAGAWA_YOSHIMOTO_NAME">
			<Text>Imagawa Yoshimoto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_IMAGAWA_YOSHIMOTO_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Daimyo of the Imagawa Clan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_IMAGAWA_YOSHIMOTO_LIVED">
			<Text>1519 - 1560 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_IMAGAWA_YOSHIMOTO_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_IMAGAWA_YOSHIMOTO_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Imagawa Yoshimoto, born in 1519, was a renowned daimyo and the leader of the Imagawa clan during the Sengoku period in Japan. He ascended to power at a young age and quickly established himself as a prominent figure in the region of Suruga. Under his leadership, the Imagawa clan expanded its influence, forming alliances with other powerful clans such as the Takeda and the Hojo.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Yoshimoto was known for his strategic prowess and diplomatic skills. He utilized a combination of military might and political maneuvering to strengthen his position. He built an extensive network of alliances and vassals, securing the loyalty of neighboring clans and expanding his territories. His reputation as a capable leader and shrewd diplomat earned him the respect of his allies and the fear of his enemies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_IMAGAWA_YOSHIMOTO_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Campaign on Kyoto and Death</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADERS_IMAGAWA_YOSHIMOTO_TEXT_2">
			<Text>In 1560, Yoshimoto set his sights on further territorial expansion and made a fateful decision to march towards Kyoto, the capital of Japan. However, his ambitions were cut short when he encountered Oda Nobunaga, a rising warlord who defied Yoshimoto's expectations. In a daring surprise attack known as the Battle of Okehazama, Nobunaga's forces ambushed Yoshimoto's army, leading to the daimyo's untimely demise. Yoshimoto's death was a significant turning point in the Sengoku period and marked the beginning of Oda Nobunaga's rise to power.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In 1560, Yoshimoto set his sights on further territorial expansion and made a fateful decision to march towards Kyoto, the capital of Japan. However, his ambitions were cut short when he encountered Oda Nobunaga, a rising warlord who defied Yoshimoto's expectations. In a daring surprise attack known as the Battle of Okehazama, Nobunaga's forces ambushed Yoshimoto's army, leading to the daimyo's untimely demise. Yoshimoto's death was a significant turning point in the Sengoku period and marked the beginning of Oda Nobunaga's rise to power.</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<!-- Greetings -->

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Greetings, I am Shimazu Yoshihiro, the daimyo of the Shimazu clan. Our clan highly values loyalty and strength. If you honor your agreements, our clans shall forge a legendary alliance. However, should you betray your word, your clan will crumble beneath the weight of our steel.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Welcome to the camp of the Shimazu. Our mastery of the katana is renowned throughout all of Japan. Interfere with our ambition, and you shall witness firsthand the consequences.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>It is a honor to meet another leader. I am Shimazu Yoshihiro, and I command the full respect of all of my generals. Disloyalty is a festering wound that erodes the foundation of society.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_SHIMAZU_YOSHIHIRO_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>You have crushed my armies in battle. Even the most loyal commanders were not enough to defeat you. It is time for me to join my ancestors.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_OTOMO_SORIN_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>May the grace of God fall upon you. I am Otomo Sorin, and I will rest for nothing in my pursuit to bring salvation to all of Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_OTOMO_SORIN_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>I am honored to be in your presence. The Otomo have embraced the teachings of God and welcome all new followers. Will you join me in prayer?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_OTOMO_SORIN_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>Welcome, great leader! I am Otomo Sorin, leader of the righteous Otomo clan. Only through prayer can we seek to absolve each other of our sins. Shall you join us?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_OTOMO_SORIN_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>How can this be? Despite my best efforts, you have defeated me. But the grace of God shall guide me through the afterlife.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_MORI_MOTONARI_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>You step into the lands of the Mori. We invite you to share in the bounty of the sea. If you act with dishonor, our ships will crush you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_MORI_MOTONARI_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Well met. I am Mori Motonari, feared daimyo of clan Mori. Our wisdom is seafaring is unmatched. For your sake, I hope you will never have to find out.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_MORI_MOTONARI_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>Welcome to our lands. My name is Mori Motonari. I have heard the call of the waves, and they will carry me to my claim of Shogun.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_MORI_MOTONARI_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>The tides have shifted against my favor. Your triumph is remarkable. It is now time for me to join my ancestors.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Hello, there. You step into the presence of Chosokabe Motochika, warlord of Shikoku, and rightful claimant of Shogun. Have you come to bend the knee?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>You stand before Chosokabe Motochika, warlord of Shikoku, and future Shogun of Japan. Shall you join us in crushing our foes, or join the many graves of men who tried to challenge me?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>Greetings. For generations the Chosokabe have ruled over Shikoku. It is time for us to claim the Shogunate. Will you call your banners in support of us, or surrender your provinces to my eventual domination?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_CHOSOKABE_MOTOCHIKA_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>We have fought bravely and lost. My ambition of the Shogunate has been crushed. I accept defeat and choose to die with honor by the blade.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_UESUGI_KENSHIN_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Hello there! The Uesugi seek to live in harmony with the kami. Would you like to visit our shrine and join us in our worship?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_UESUGI_KENSHIN_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Welcome to the land of the Uesugi. I am Uesugi Kenshin, disciple of Bishamonten. Have you come to marvel at our places of worship?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_UESUGI_KENSHIN_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>You stand before the Dragon of Echigo, Uesugi Kenshin! I follow in the footsteps of the great warrior-king Bishamonten!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_UESUGI_KENSHIN_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>You have defeated me in combat. Have I misplaced my faith in the gods?</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I am Takeda Shingen, warlord of Kai. Do not interfere with my ambition, and you will live to see another day.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>You stand in the presence of Takeda Shingen. Our cavalry are feared amongst all men. Pray you do not have to learn why.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>The proud people of the Takeda clan greet you. I hope you are a strong ally or worthy opponent!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>You have crushed my cavalry in combat, and left my clan to ruin. I know what must be done now.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>I was outmaneuverd on the battlefield, and now I must pay the price. I wish you luck in your quest for the Shogunate.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TAKEDA_SHINGEN_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>With my armies defeated, there is nothing left that stands in your way. Remember me as you crush your enemies.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_HOJO_UJIYASU_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>The stalwart Hojo people greet you. We invite you to marvel at our mighty castles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_HOJO_UJIYASU_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>I am Hojo Ujiyasu, warlord of the Hojo. I am loyal to my friends, death to my enemies. Which are you?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_HOJO_UJIYASU_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>Welcome! I am Hojo Ujiyasu, ruler of the Hojo clan. Have you come to pay tribute?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_HOJO_UJIYASU_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>I am defeated on the field of battle. I congratulate you on your victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_HOJO_UJIYASU_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>Please end this dishonor to my family... to my people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_HOJO_UJIYASU_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>Your were far stronger on the battlefield than I anticipated. Now, I know what I must do.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I am Tokugawa Ieyasu. I hope you prove to be a valuable ally.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>I am Tokugawa Ieyasu. Nothing happens here without my say.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>I am Tokugawa Ieyasu. Perseverance has made me what I am today. If our descendants want to be strong, they must too study patience.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_DECLAREWAR_1">
			<Text>Years of patience and planning have come to this. It is time to die!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_DECLAREWAR_2">
			<Text>The sharp-edged sword cuts through the void, and within the raging fire, a cool wind blows. Prepare to die.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>Most men rush to die by the sword. I've chosen a more patient route, and patience requires good allies. I'd like to make a public Declaration of Friendship, informing the other clans of our alliance. What do you say?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>The summer grasses are all that remains of warriors' dreams. I congratulate you on your victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>A great calamity has befallen my people. I know what must be done. Let me rest in peace. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_IEYASU_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>I thought patience was the key to success. You have proven me wrong. And for that, I congratulate you.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_RENNYO_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>It is good to meet you. I am Rennyo, leader of the Jodo Shinshu Buddhists. I hope you have time to listen to our teachings.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_RENNYO_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Hello! I am Rennyo, and my teachings have spread far and wide amongst the Ikko-Ikki. I do not advocate for violence, but we must defend ourselves if deemed necessary.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_RENNYO_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>In the name of the Ikko-Ikki people, I offer you my hand in friendship!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_RENNYO_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>My people's fervor has finally burnt out. I congratulate you in your victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_RENNYO_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>You have destroyed our people, but you will never break the spirit of the Ikko-Ikki!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_RENNYO_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>Our temples have fallen. How could this have happened?</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_DATE_MASAMUNE_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Welcome, Stranger! I am Date Masamune, the One-Eyed Dragon of Oshu. My achievements on the battlefield are numerous. Are yours?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_DATE_MASAMUNE_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Welcome to the land of the Date. Our time is precious; I hope you have not come to waste mine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_DATE_MASAMUNE_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>You stand before the feared warrior, Date Masamune! I ripped my eye out when I was a young boy. Do not think I won't do the same to you, if necessary.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_DATE_MASAMUNE_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>I am defeated? How could this be? I was invincible!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_DATE_MASAMUNE_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>I thought I couldn't lose on the battlefield. You have proven me wrong. I congratulate you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_LEADER_DATE_MASAMUNE_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>The title of Shogun was mine for the taking! This is outrageous! How could I have lost to the likes of you?</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>
