<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 7/8/2023 11:25:20 AM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_RELIGION_CHRISTIANITY">
			<Text>Christianity</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_RELIGION_CHRISTIANITY_PEDIA">
			<Text>Christianity originated in the 1st century CE with the life, death, and resurrection of Jesus Christ in the Roman province of Judea. The teachings of Jesus, as recorded in the New Testament, emphasized love, forgiveness, and salvation through faith. Christianity began as a small Jewish sect but soon expanded beyond the Jewish community, attracting followers across the Roman Empire.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the early centuries of the Common Era, Christianity started to spread eastward along trade routes into Asia. Communities of Christians established themselves in places like Persia (modern-day Iran) and India. These early Christian communities were known as the Church of the East or the Nestorian Church.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In the late 15th and 16th centuries, the Age of Exploration saw European powers venture into uncharted territories, seeking new trade routes and territories. European exploration was accompanied by a zeal for spreading Christianity, as the Catholic Church wanted to convert people to the faith and counter the influence of other religious traditions.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The first contact between Europeans and Japan took place in 1543 when a Portuguese ship, blown off course, landed on the island of Tanegashima. The Portuguese traders, bringing with them firearms and other novelties, piqued the interest of the local daimyō (feudal lords) and merchants. This initial encounter laid the groundwork for future interactions.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The key figure in the introduction of Christianity to Japan was the Spanish Jesuit missionary, St. Francis Xavier. He arrived in Kagoshima, Japan, in 1549, along with two companions. Xavier and his fellow Jesuits began preaching Christianity and soon found some success, especially among peasants and merchants who were open to new ideas.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Jesuit missionaries adapted their approach to Japanese culture and language, gaining further acceptance among the population. They translated Christian texts and teachings into Japanese and employed various strategies to engage with the locals, including adopting aspects of Japanese customs while accommodating certain Shinto and Buddhist practices. The missionaries also built schools and medical facilities, which further endeared them to the local populace.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Despite initial successes, Christianity faced challenges as it encountered the established Japanese social and religious order. Christianity's rapid spread raised concerns among ruling authorities, including the shogunate and powerful Buddhist institutions. They perceived Christianity as a threat to their authority and to the stability of the social hierarchy.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In 1587, Toyotomi Hideyoshi, the powerful warlord and de facto ruler of Japan, issued the Bateren Tsuiho (Ban on Jesuits), an edict expelling missionaries from Japan. This was followed by a series of subsequent edicts that intensified the persecution of Christians. The situation worsened after Hideyoshi's death, culminating in the Shimabara Rebellion in 1637-38, led by oppressed Christian peasants.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Shimabara Rebellion further solidified the fear of Christianity among the ruling class. In 1639, the Tokugawa shogunate, which had recently come to power, implemented a policy of national isolation called the Sakoku Edict. This policy aimed to limit foreign influence and control the spread of Christianity. Foreigners were expelled, and Christianity was officially banned, with Christians facing severe persecution and forced to practice their faith in secret.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The period of isolation lasted for over two centuries, and during this time, Christianity largely went underground, with secret Christian communities, known as "Kakure Kirishitan," preserving their faith in secrecy.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It was only in the mid-19th century, when Japan opened its doors to the world again, that Christianity was allowed to resurface. Protestant and Catholic missionaries re-entered the country and began their evangelizing efforts anew. Today, Christianity remains a minority religion in Japan, with about 1-2% of the population identifying as Christians, coexisting alongside Shintoism and Buddhism as major religious traditions in the country.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_RELIGION_JODO_SHINSHU">
			<Text>Jodo Shinshu Buddhism</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_RELIGION_JODO_SHINSHU_PEDIA">
			<Text>Jodo Shinshu Buddhism, also known as Shin Buddhism, is a school of Mahayana Buddhism that originated in Japan. It is centered around the teachings of Shinran Shonin, a Buddhist monk who lived in the 13th century. Jodo Shinshu is distinguished by its emphasis on the concept of "other power" (tariki) and the practice of reciting the Nembutsu, which is the name of Amida Buddha.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The term "Jodo Shinshu" translates to "True Pure Land School" and reflects the school's focus on the Pure Land teachings. According to Jodo Shinshu beliefs, salvation and liberation from suffering are attained through the grace and compassion of Amida Buddha. It is believed that by entrusting oneself to Amida Buddha and reciting the Nembutsu, one can be reborn in the Pure Land, a realm of enlightenment and ultimate liberation.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The teachings of Jodo Shinshu emphasize the inherent limitations of human efforts and the reliance on Amida Buddha's wisdom and compassion. This perspective is grounded in the understanding that individuals are inherently filled with blind passions and cannot achieve enlightenment through their own power alone. Instead, they rely on Amida Buddha's vow to save all beings and the transformative power of the Nembutsu.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Jodo Shinshu Buddhism has its roots in the Tendai school of Buddhism but developed its distinct teachings and practices under Shinran Shonin's guidance. Shinran emphasized the universality and accessibility of Amida Buddha's salvation, stating that it is available to all beings regardless of their spiritual abilities or social status. This inclusivity and egalitarianism have contributed to the widespread popularity of Jodo Shinshu Buddhism in Japan and beyond.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The practice of Jodo Shinshu revolves around reciting the Nembutsu, which is the repetition of the phrase "Namu Amida Butsu" (meaning "I take refuge in Amida Buddha"). Through the sincere recitation of the Nembutsu, practitioners express their gratitude for Amida Buddha's compassion and seek rebirth in the Pure Land. This practice is often performed in both formal settings, such as temples, and in daily life as a way to cultivate mindfulness and gratitude.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Jodo Shinshu Buddhism has a strong institutional presence in Japan, with numerous temples and organizations dedicated to its teachings. The Hongwanji, headquartered in Kyoto, is the largest sect within Jodo Shinshu and serves as its central organization. Outside of Japan, Jodo Shinshu has gained followers and established temples in various countries, contributing to its global presence.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As a prominent school of Buddhism, Jodo Shinshu continues to offer spiritual guidance, support, and a sense of community to its practitioners. With its emphasis on Amida Buddha's compassion and the Nembutsu practice, Jodo Shinshu Buddhism provides a path for individuals seeking solace, spiritual growth, and liberation from the cycle of suffering.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_ANCESTOR_WORSHIP">
			<Text>+2 [ICON_PEACE] Faith and +2 [ICON_CULTURE] from World Wonders.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_ANCESTOR_WORSHIP_SHORT">
			<Text>Ancestor Worship</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_PAPAL_PRIMACY">
			<Text>Receive +8 [ICON_PEACE] Faith and [ICON_GOLD] Gold for each Follower converted when a Missionary spreads this Religion to a City.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_PAPAL_PRIMACY_SHORT">
			<Text>Papal Primacy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_POPULISM">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_PEACE] Faith per 3 Followers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_POPULISM_SHORT">
			<Text>Populism</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_KAMI">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture per 4 Followers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_KAMI_SHORT">
			<Text>Kami</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_PURE_LAND_THOUGHT">
			<Text>Religion spreads 30% faster and to cities 30% further away.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_PURE_LAND_THOUGHT_SHORT">
			<Text>Pure Land Thought</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_TITHE">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold for every 4 followers of this religion</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_TITHE_SHORT">
			<Text>Tithe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_MONASTERIES">
			<Text>Use [ICON_PEACE] Faith to purchase Jodo Shinshu Temples. (+2 [ICON_PEACE] Faith, +2 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture, more religious pressure)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_MONASTERIES_SHORT">
			<Text>Jodo Shinshu Temples</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_HOLY_WARRIORS">
			<Text>Use [ICON_PEACE] Faith to purchase land units</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_HOLY_WARRIORS_SHORT">
			<Text>Holy Warriors</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_RELIGIOUS_COMMUNITY">
			<Text>+1% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production for each follower (max +15%)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_RELIGIOUS_COMMUNITY_SHORT">
			<Text>Religious Community</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_MISSIONARY_ZEAL">
			<Text>Missionary conversion strength +25%</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_MISSIONARY_ZEAL_SHORT">
			<Text>Missionary Zeal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_DEFENDER_FAITH">
			<Text>+20% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength near friendly cities that follow this religion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_DEFENDER_FAITH_SHORT">
			<Text>Defender of the Faith</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_JUST_WAR">
			<Text>+20% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength near enemy cities that follow this religion</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_JUST_WAR_SHORT">
			<Text>Just War</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_HOLY_ORDER">
			<Text>Missionaries and Inquisitors cost 30% less [ICON_PEACE] Faith</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_BELIEF_HOLY_ORDER_SHORT">
			<Text>Holy Order</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>