<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 5/31/2023 8:04:49 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_YARI_ASHIGARU">
			<Text>Yari Ashigaru</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_YARI_ASHIGARU_TEXT">
			<Text>The term "Yari Ashigaru" refers to foot soldiers armed with the yari, a long spear that became their signature weapon. The yari, typically measuring around six to twelve feet in length, provided reach and versatility in combat. The Ashigaru were trained in the art of yarijutsu, spear techniques that emphasized precision strikes and coordination within their ranks.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Initially, the Yari Ashigaru were primarily peasants and commoners who were conscripted or enlisted to serve in the armies of daimyo. These foot soldiers provided a means for daimyo to field large armies at a relatively low cost, as the Ashigaru were less expensive to equip and maintain than the samurai warriors.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Over time, the Yari Ashigaru gained recognition for their discipline, effectiveness, and adaptability on the battlefield. They were known for their ability to form tight spear formations, called "yari wall" or "spear hedge," which created a formidable barrier against cavalry charges and infantry assaults.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Yari Ashigaru were also skilled in siege warfare, often wielding their spears as makeshift pikes to repel castle defenders or breach enemy fortifications. They were adept at employing tactical formations, such as the "crane wing" or "flying geese," to encircle and overwhelm enemy forces.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The prominence of the Yari Ashigaru reached its peak during the Battle of Nagashino in 1575. Led by Oda Nobunaga and his strategist, Toyotomi Hideyoshi, a combined force of Ashigaru and matchlock gunners successfully defended against the cavalry charges of the Takeda clan. The battle showcased the effectiveness of the Ashigaru's disciplined formations and their integration with firearms.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As the Sengoku Jidai period came to a close and the Tokugawa shogunate was established, the role of the Yari Ashigaru underwent significant changes. With the Tokugawa shoguns seeking to stabilize Japan and establish a strict social hierarchy, the Ashigaru became more regulated and their status became more defined. They were often assigned to specific domains, serving as part of the standing armies under the control of the daimyo.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_YARI_ASHIGARU_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Yari Ashigaru is the cheapest and earliest unit in the game. Yari Ashigaru allow you to quickly build up and field an army, and can hold their own against Cavalry, but they will quickly fall to more heavily armored foes.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_YARI_ASHIGARU_HELP">
			<Text>Weak, cheap early game Unit with a +100% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat bonus Mounted Units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_YARI_SAMURAI">
			<Text>Yari Samurai</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_YARI_SAMURAI_TEXT">
			<Text>These elite samurai were known for their exceptional proficiency in spear combat, utilizing the yari's reach and versatility to devastating effect. They formed the backbone of many feudal armies, employing disciplined formations and strategic maneuvers to overcome their opponents. Renowned for their unwavering loyalty, strict code of honor, and mastery of battlefield tactics, Yari Samurai were formidable forces on the battlefield, capable of breaking enemy lines and securing victories for their clans. Their skill with the yari made them respected and feared adversaries, embodying the essence of samurai warriors.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_YARI_SAMURAI_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Yari Samurai fare better in combat against more improved opponents compared to their Ashigaru counterparts. Utilize Yari Samurai when you need to counter a lot of enemy Mounted units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_YARI_SAMURAI_HELP">
			<Text>Expensive, powerful Samurai Unit with a +100% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat bonus vs. Mounted Units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_WARRIOR_MONK">
			<Text>Warrior Monk</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_WARRIOR_MONK_TEXT">
			<Text>The Sohei were warrior monks of medieval Japan, known for their martial skills and spiritual devotion. These disciplined and formidable warriors were deeply rooted in Buddhist teachings, combining their religious practices with combat training. Clad in distinctive robes and armed with traditional weapons such as naginatas and bows, the Sohei served as protectors of temples and monastic communities. Their unwavering loyalty to their religious beliefs and their prowess on the battlefield made them a force to be reckoned with, embodying the harmonious blend of spiritual enlightenment and martial strength.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_WARRIOR_MONK_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Warrior Monk is a terrifying melee unit only available in Cities where the Buddhist faith is most prominent. Warrior monks are exceptional in combat against traditional melee units like the Yari Ashigaru and Katana Samurai, but they are very vulnerable to ranged attacks from both bows and guns. Be selective with your targets with the Warrior Monk, and they will be a fantastic addition to your army.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_WARRIOR_MONK_HELP">
			<Text>Feared warrior with a +100% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat bonus vs. both Melee and Mounted Units. Weak to Gunpowder and Archery units. Can only be purchased with [ICON_PEACE] Faith, and is only available to [ICON_RELIGION_SHINTO] Shinto and [ICON_RELIGION_JODO_SHINSHU] Jodo Shinshu clans.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_KATANA_ASHIGARU">
			<Text>Katana Ashigaru</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_KATANA_ASHIGARU_TEXT">
			<Text>Consisting of peasant and commoner warriors, the ashigaru formed the backbone of many daimyo armies, bringing numerical strength, discipline, and adaptability to the battlefield. Equipped with an array of weapons such as spears, bows, katanas, and matchlock guns, they were adept at forming tight formations, repelling enemy assaults, and executing siege warfare. While lacking the social status of the samurai, ashigaru proved their worth through their resilience, tactical prowess, and ability to work in harmony with other units, leaving an indelible mark on the military history of feudal Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_KATANA_ASHIGARU_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Katana Ashigaru is a formidable early-game combat unit that is useful for crushing weaker units, such as the Yari Ashigaru. They are most effective in capturing cities early on since they do not suffer combat penalties against them, unlike mounted units, while maintaining a higher combat strength than the Yari Ashigaru. However, Katana Ashigaru may struggle against more heavily armored units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_KATANA_ASHIGARU_HELP">
			<Text>Cheap Melee Unit that receives a +50% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat bonus vs. Melee Units and a +33% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat bonus vs. Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_JAPANESE_SAMURAI_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Katana Samurai is an expensive Melee Unit that can dominate the Japanese battlefield against other Melee units. Use Samurai to lead attacks against enemy Cities, but avoid losing them as replacing them is extremely expensive.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_HELP_SAMURAI">
			<Text>Powerful Samurai Melee Unit that receives a +50% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat bonus vs. Melee Units and a +33% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat bonus vs. Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_MUSKETMAN_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Musketman is the first unit in the scenario that can replace the Ashigaru as the mainstay of armies due to their low cost but high strength. Musketman can hold their own against Samurai units, but you can field a lot more Musketman than other types of units. However, the Musketman is vulnerable to attacks from archers and cavalry.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_HELP_MUSKETMAN">
			<Text>Cheap melee Unit that is strong against Melee units but weak against Cavalry and Archers. +50% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat bonus vs. Melee Units, and an additional +50% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat bonus vs. Warrior Monks.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_OTOMO_PORTUGUESE_TERCO">
			<Text>Portuguese Terco</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_OTOMO_PORTUGUESE_TERCO_TEXT">
			<Text>The Portuguese terco was a military formation and tactical unit utilized by the Portuguese during the Age of Discovery and their overseas colonial ventures. It consisted of a well-organized infantry unit composed of musketeers, pikemen, and officers. The terco was known for its disciplined formations, firepower, and versatility in combat. Musketeers armed with matchlock firearms provided ranged support, while pikemen wielding long spears defended against enemy charges. The terço's effectiveness was demonstrated in various conflicts, including battles in Asia, Africa, and South America. The Portuguese terco played a significant role in expanding and maintaining Portuguese influence overseas, representing a formidable military force during the time of their empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_OTOMO_PORTUGUESE_TERCO_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Portuguese Terco is the Otomo clan unique unit, replacing the Musketman. This Unit is stronger in combat than the Musketman and fights at a higher strength against mounted units. It is also available at Theology, significantly earlier than Gunpowder. However, the Portuguese Terco is more expensive to build.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SENGOKU_SCENARIO_UNIT_OTOMO_PORTUGUESE_TERCO_HELP">
			<Text>Dominant military Unit that is strong against Melee units, but weak against Archers. Only the Otomo clan may build it. This Unit is available in the Technology Tree earlier and has a higher [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength than the Musketman which it replaces, as well as a Bonus vs Mounted promotion. However it is also more expensive to build.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIGHT_CAVALRY">
			<Text>Light Cavalry</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LIGHT_CAVALRY_TEXT">
			<Text>These mounted warriors played a crucial role in reconnaissance, skirmishes, and hit-and-run tactics. Lightly armored and armed with weapons such as bows, spears, or swords, they excelled in mobility and speed, allowing them to swiftly maneuver through enemy lines and exploit vulnerabilities. Their primary objective was to disrupt enemy formations, harass supply lines, and provide crucial support to the main forces. While they lacked the heavy armor and brute force of their samurai counterparts, the Light Cavalry's agility and strategic finesse made them invaluable assets in the ever-shifting landscape of feudal Japan's warfare.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIGHT_CAVALRY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Light Cavalry is a fast and powerful mounted unit, utilizing its mobility to attack weaker units such as archers or injured foes, and then retreating before they face counterattacks from more formidable enemies, particularly Yari units. Light Cavalry are highly ineffective when assaulting cities and should instead be deployed to break enemy lines, allowing more powerful units to siege cities. However, caution must be exercised when encountering enemy Yari units, as they can quickly kill Light Cavalry.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIGHT_CAVALRY_HELP">
			<Text>Fast and powerful Mounted unit. Weak to Yari units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HORSE_ARCHER">
			<Text>Horse Archer</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_HORSE_ARCHER_TEXT">
			<Text>Horse archery, known as "yabusame" or "inuoumono" in feudal Japan, was a skillful and revered martial art practiced by elite warriors called "samurai." This ancient tradition originated from continental Asia, and the Japanese adopted and refined it to suit their unique combat style. Horse archers were highly regarded for their exceptional horsemanship and marksmanship, capable of firing arrows with remarkable precision while riding at high speeds. The bow they used was called a "yumi," which was longer than the traditional bows used by infantry, allowing for greater accuracy and range. These skilled horse archers played a pivotal role in battles, skirmishes, and hunting expeditions, showcasing their deadly proficiency in both open field engagements and guerrilla warfare.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Throughout Japan's feudal period, horse archers served as essential components of samurai armies, particularly during the Sengoku (Warring States) period from the 15th to 17th centuries. They were valued for their mobility, enabling them to perform hit-and-run tactics, surprise attacks, and encircle enemies. Their strategic significance in conflicts led to extensive training, and some domains even held yabusame competitions to foster and demonstrate the mastery of this art. Although the advent of firearms and the centralization of power under the Tokugawa shogunate brought changes to warfare, the legacy of horse archers endured, exemplifying their lasting impact on Japan's military history.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HORSE_ARCHER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Horse archers are fast ranged units, deadly on open terrain. As a mounted unit, the Horse Archer is vulnerable to Yari units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HORSE_ARCHER_HELP">
			<Text>A fast Ranged Unit used for hit-and-run attacks.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HEAVY_CAVALRY">
			<Text>Heavy Cavalry</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_HEAVY_CAVALRY_TEXT">
			<Text>These elite mounted warriors were heavily armored and armed with weapons such as yari (spears) and katana (swords), enabling them to deliver devastating charges and engage in close combat. With their superior armor and weaponry, Heavy Cavalry were capable of breaking through enemy lines, shattering formations, and instilling fear in their opponents. Their role extended beyond sheer brute force, as they also provided protection for commanders, executed flanking maneuvers, and pursued routing enemies. While fewer in number compared to other cavalry units, Heavy Cavalry commanded respect and played a pivotal role in shaping the outcome of battles during this tumultuous era of feudal Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HEAVY_CAVALRY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>One of the most feared units on the battlefield, Heavy Cavalry sacrifice some of their mobility to deal more damage in direct combat. Employ Heavy Cavalry to eliminate opposing threats across the battlefield, yet exercise caution in the presence of Yari units, as they can make quick work of your cavalry.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HEAVY_CAVALRY_HELP">
			<Text>A strong Mounted unit that sacrifices extra mobility for better performance in combat. Weak to Yari units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TOKUGAWA_MOUNTED_GUNNER">
			<Text>Mounted Gunner</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TOKUGAWA_MOUNTED_GUNNER_TEXT">
			<Text>The Mounted Gunners were an elite and highly specialized military force during Japan's Edo period (1603-1868). Established by Tokugawa Ieyasu, the founder of the Tokugawa shogunate, the mounted gunners were renowned for their exceptional horsemanship and mastery of firearms, particularly matchlock muskets (teppo). This formidable cavalry unit played a crucial role in maintaining the Tokugawa regime's control over the country, participating in various battles and campaigns. Their combination of swift maneuverability and the devastating firepower of their muskets made them a force to be reckoned with on the battlefield, ensuring the Tokugawa shogunate's supremacy for over two centuries.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TOKUGAWA_MOUNTED_GUNNER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Mounted Gunner is the Tokugawa clan's unique unit, replacing the Heavy Cavalry. They are much stronger than the regular Heavy Cavalry, and can move one hex more than the Heavy Cavalry, making it an incredibly powerful and dangerous unit. Use Mounted Gunners to crush the enemy's units, and then use your infantry to capture their undefended cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TOKUGAWA_MOUNTED_GUNNER_HELP">
			<Text>Mounted Unit capable of crushing their contemporary foes. Only the Tokugawa may build it. In addition to a higher [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength, the Tokugawa Mounted Gunners are faster than the Heavy Cavalry, which it replaces.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOW_ASHIGARU">
			<Text>Bow Ashigaru</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOW_ASHIGARU_TEXT">
			<Text>Bow Ashigaru were peasant warriors armed with bows, serving as a vital component of feudal Japan's military forces during the Sengoku Jidai period. Despite their humble origins, these commoners displayed remarkable skill in archery and played a significant role in ranged warfare. Equipped with their trusty bows, they unleashed volleys of arrows upon the enemy, utilizing their accuracy and range to deadly effect. Though lacking the social status and privileges of the samurai, the Bow Ashigaru proved their worth through their dedication and proficiency with the bow, underscoring the importance of commoners in shaping the outcome of battles during this era of intense conflict in Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOW_ASHIGARU_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Bow Ashigaru are cheap and cost-effective to produce, provided they are protected on the battlefield from melee units, especially mounted units. Bow Ashigaru are most useful when defending cities in the early game, where they are cheap to produce and able to rain down fire from protected positions, but weak on the open terrain where they are susceptible to attacks from mounted units. Bow Ashigaru will be vulnerable to other ranged attacks, so they will not be effective in sieging enemy cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOW_ASHIGARU_HELP">
			<Text>Cheap ranged Unit, capable of attacking enemies at a distance. Their low [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength makes them vulnerable to melee attacks, so they must be protected in combat.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOW_SAMURAI">
			<Text>Bow Samurai</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOW_SAMURAI_TEXT">
			<Text>Bow Samurai were elite warriors of feudal Japan who excelled in both archery and swordsmanship. These highly skilled and disciplined soldiers were among the most versatile and respected fighters on the battlefield during the Sengoku Jidai period. Armed with both a bow and a katana, they possessed the ability to engage enemies from a distance or in close-quarters combat. The Bow Samurai's mastery of archery allowed them to rain down precise and deadly volleys of arrows upon their foes, while their proficiency in swordplay ensured they were formidable opponents in melee engagements. With their well-rounded skill set, the Bow Samurai played a crucial role in strategic maneuvers, defensive actions, and decisive offensives, leaving a lasting impact on the military history of feudal Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOW_SAMURAI_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Bow Samurai are expert marksmen, capable of dealing devastating damage to units from range. Although they are less effective in melee combat compared to contemporary melee units, Bow Samurai are quite capable of defending themselves against Ashigaru units and light cavalry, making them a formidable force on the battlefield. To ensure their protection, position your archers alongside heavily armed melee units and take advantage of defensive bonuses provided by hills and forests. With this strategic placement, you can unleash a relentless barrage of arrows upon your enemies, turning the tide of battle in your favor.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOW_SAMURAI_HELP">
			<Text>Powerful ranged Unit, able to attack enemies from a distance. Capable of defending themselves in close combat, but less effective than other melee units in combat.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOW_KOBAYA">
			<Text>Bow Kobaya</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOW_KOBAYA_TEXT">
			<Text>During the Sengoku Jidai, ships were mostly made from wood, occasionally augmented by thick bamboo or iron plates. This made them inflammable, and it was quite common to set fire to a vessel prior to boarding it. Archers would use fire arrows, or bombs would be thrown, all in the interests of making life as difficult as possible for the defenders. However, boarding actions were the most important tactic of war at sea, and everything else was subordinated to them. This was just as well, as incendiary weapons lacked the power of cannons, which were hardly common. Japanese naval warfare never went the same way as European naval tactics, with ships becoming gun platforms and fighting at a distance for the most part.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOW_KOBAYA_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Bow Kobaya is the only naval unit in the game with a ranged attack. The Bow Kobaya is useful for weakening enemy ships from a distance, which can then be captured by more powerful melee ships. It cannot enter Deep Ocean hexes.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOW_KOBAYA_HELP">
			<Text>Early Sengoku Naval Unit used to wrest control of the seas with its ranged attack.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BUNE">
			<Text>Seki Bune</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BUNE_TEXT">
			<Text>The Seki Bune, also known as "stone ships," were a unique type of warship that emerged in Japan during the Sengoku period. These vessels were named after the stones that were used as ballast to provide stability. The Seki Bune were characterized by their flat-bottomed design, which allowed them to navigate shallow waters and river systems. They were primarily used for riverine warfare and coastal defense, providing a tactical advantage in battles fought in such environments. The Seki Bune were equipped with a combination of cannons, archers, and spearmen, making them formidable in both long-range and close-quarter engagements. Their compact size and maneuverability made them highly effective in navigating narrow waterways and launching surprise attacks. The Seki Bune played a significant role in the conflicts of the Sengoku period, particularly during battles along river systems and coastal regions. Their unique design and specialized capabilities made them an important asset for daimyo seeking to control strategic waterways and defend their territories.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BUNE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Seki Bune is the first naval melee unit available to clans in the game. It is dominant on the seas until the arrival of the Atakebune, and should be used to attack other naval units and cities to secure your Sea Trade Routes which will kickstart your clan's economy.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_BUNE_HELP">
			<Text>Sengoku Naval Unit used to wrest control of the seas through melee attacks on naval units and cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ATAKEBUNE">
			<Text>Atakebune</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ATAKEBUNE_TEXT">
			<Text>The Atakebune was a type of large Japanese warship that emerged during the late Sengoku period in the 16th century. These formidable vessels were designed with a distinctive appearance, featuring a high forecastle and aftcastle, multiple decks, and sturdy construction. The Atakebune played a crucial role in naval warfare, offering the advantage of both firepower and defensive capabilities. They were equipped with numerous cannons, matchlock guns, and bowmen, allowing them to engage enemy ships from a distance. The Atakebune saw action in various conflicts, including battles between rival daimyo and clashes with foreign powers, particularly during the attempts of the wokou pirates to invade Japan. Their imposing presence and strategic significance made the Atakebune an integral part of Japan's maritime defense and expansion during the Sengoku period, leaving a lasting legacy in naval history.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ATAKEBUNE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Atakebune is the strongest melee naval unit available to clans in the game, outclassing the Seki Bune before it, but very expensive to build and maintain. Use Atakebunes to attack and capture enemy coastal cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ATAKEBUNE_HELP">
			<Text>Strongest Naval Melee unit in the game. The Atakebune is heavily-armored and dominates ships and cities at close range, allowing it to help capture late-game coastal cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ESCALADERS">
			<Text>Escaladers</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ESCALADERS_TEXT">
			<Text>The use of siege ladders was a common tactic employed in warfare to breach the fortified walls of Japanese cities during various periods of history. In feudal Japan, when attacking a well-defended city, invading forces would often utilize siege ladders as an effective means to scale the walls and gain entry into the city. Siege ladders were typically long, portable wooden structures with rungs or steps that could be propped against the walls to allow warriors to climb and enter the city. These ladders were often accompanied by other siege weapons, such as battering rams or catapults, to weaken the defenses and create openings for the attacking forces. The use of siege ladders required careful planning, coordination, and often involved fierce and intense fighting as defenders sought to repel the invaders from breaching their city walls.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ESCALADERS_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Use Escaladers to knock down the defenses of a city. They have the Cover I promotion to keep them safe from ranged units; attack them with melee units to defeat them.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ESCALADERS_HELP">
			<Text>Siege unit deadly at melee attacks versus cities.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>